<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE tmx SYSTEM "tmx11.dtd">
<tmx version="1.1">
  <header creationtool="OmegaT" o-tmf="OmegaT TMX" adminlang="EN-US" datatype="plaintext" creationtoolversion="3.1.9_4" segtype="sentence" srclang="EN-US"/>
  <body>
<!-- Default translations -->
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>(As described earlier in this chapter, psychological research has demonstrated such a belief to be inadequate.) In their praiseworthy pursuit of evidence in very serious and difficult to solve cases some police officers found that witnesses who were hypnotized then recalled information about the crime that they had not previously recalled.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T123308Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151009T141453Z">
        <seg>(Như từng đề cập lúc trước trong chương này, các nghiên cứu về tâm lý học đã chứng minh niềm tin trên không hề chính xác.) Trong quá trình nỗ lực rất đáng tuyên dương tìm kiếm bằng chứng trong những vụ án nghiêm trọng và khó phá, một số cảnh sát nhận thấy có vài nhân chứng sau khi bị thôi miên có thể nhớ lại thông tin mà trước đó họ không hề nhớ. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>A few studies have examined sex offenders’ narratives of their offences and there are general studies of prisoner language but these have yet to find applications.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T152450Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T152450Z">
        <seg>Một vài nghiên cứu đã xem xét câu chuyện của tội phạm tình dục về hành vi phạm tội và có những nghiên cứu chung về ngôn ngữ nhưng các tù nhân nhưng vẫn chưa ứng dụng được.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>A further issue often given prominence by feminist researchers is the way women victims of rape are treated by the legal system.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T012314Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T012314Z">
        <seg>Các nhà nghiên cứu nữ quyền đưa ra một vấn đề nổi bật nữa là cách các nữ nạn nhân hiếp dâm được xử lý bằng hệ thống pháp luật.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>A higher crime rate might also partly be an increase in the reporting of sexual offences, which implies that people are becoming more intolerant of unacceptable &lt;t2/&gt;behaviour&lt;t3/&gt; and believe that reported offences will be taken seriously by the police and courts.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T134642Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T134642Z">
        <seg>Tỉ lệ tội phạm tăng lên có thể một phần là do sự tăng thêm về số lượng báo cáo tội ác tình dục, ám chỉ rằng mọi người đang trở nên không khoan nhượng về các hành xử không thể chấp nhận và tin rằng việc báo cáo tội ác sẽ được cảnh sát và toà án xử lí nghiêm túc.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>A history of suicide attempts/threats.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151010T061840Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151010T061840Z">
        <seg>Đã từng cố gắng tự tử.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>A number of books have been published that claim to reveal &lt;t0/&gt;behavioural&lt;t1/&gt; cues to lying.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T095411Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T095411Z">
        <seg>Nhiều cuốn sách đã được xuất bản khẳng định rằng có thể nhận thấy được&lt;t0/&gt;các dấu hiệu hành vi&lt;t1/&gt; của nói dối
</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>A senior police officer stated that ‘Sarah’s Law’ would &lt;t0/&gt;drive offenders under- ground, which would then stop criminal justice agencies from monitoring their movements or treating them.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T165142Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T165142Z">
        <seg>Một sĩ quan cảnh sát có thâm niên khẳng định rằng Luật Sarah sẽ đẩy các tên tội phạm xuống hoạt động ngầm và khiến các cơ quan công lý không tài nào giám sát hành động của họ hay xử lý họ.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>A trend consistent across the literature is that approximately twenty per cent of sexual offences are committed by adolescents.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T153911Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T153911Z">
        <seg>Một xu hướng nhất quán trong các tài liệu nghiên cứu là xấp xỉ 20 phần trăm các trường hợp phạm tội quấy rối tình dục là thanh niên.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Academic criminal psychologists working in universities have also been conducting such research.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T151853Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T151853Z">
        <seg>Các nhà tâm lý học tội phạm trong các trường đại học hiện cũng đang tiến hành các nghiên cứu tương tự.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>According to the International Centre for Prison Studies there are over 8.5 million people imprisoned worldwide.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152151Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152151Z">
        <seg>Theo như Trung tâm Nghiên cứu Nhà tù Quốc tế, có hơn 8,5 triệu người đã bị bắt giữ trên toàn thế giới.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Actions or behaviour which are now acceptable within most Western cultures – for example homosexuality and abortion – were not in the past.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T151012Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T151012Z">
        <seg>Các hành đọng hoặc lối cư xử ngày nay được chấp nhận ở phần lớn văn hóa phương Tây - ví dụ như đồng tính và phá thai - đã không được chấp nhận trước đây.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Active notification means that leaflets are sent out, people are visited by their local police, e-mails are sent to schools and community groups, and notices may be placed in local newspapers.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T162233Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T161954Z">
        <seg>Thông báo thiết thực có nghĩa là phát hành các tờ rơi, mọi người được cảnh sát địa phương thông báo, emails được gửi đến các trường học và cộng đồng, và những thông báo nào sẽ được in trên báo địa phương.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Advocates of Megan’s Law believe that active community notification will help criminal justice agencies in investigations, establish legal grounds to hold known sex offenders, deter sex offenders from committing future crimes and offer the public information that they can use to protect their children from offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T163700Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T163700Z">
        <seg>Những người tán thành Luật Megan tin rằng việc thông báo thiết thực cho cộng đồng sẽ giúp các cơ quan công lý trong việc điều tra, thiết lập lý lẽ để kiểm soát những tội phạm tình dục đã biết, ngăn cản họ khỏi việc tái phạm và đưa ra cho công chúng những thông tin mà họ có thể dùng để bảo vệ con em mình khỏi tội phạm. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>All offenders who have committed a drink-driving offence will be given the same sentence; all offenders who have raped another person will be given a similar punishment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T132505Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T132505Z">
        <seg>Tất cả những tội phạm phạm vào tội lái xe say sẽ phải chịu cùng 1 án phạt, tất cả những người phạm tội hiếp dâm sẽ chịu cùng 1 mức án.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>All sorts of security products are avail- able to help citizens to protect their homes and possessions (e.g. burglar alarms, bolts and locks), and this industry has become big business.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T144843Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T144805Z">
        <seg>Đa dạng các loại sản phẩm phục vụ cho vấn đề an ninh có mặt trên thị trường để giúp người dân bảo vệ nhà cửa và của cải của họ (như chuông báo trộm, chốt cửa và ổ khóa...), và ngành công nghiệp này đã trở thành việc buôn bán lớn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Although this is a very high number, should we really be concerned about how imprisonment affects these people?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152207Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152207Z">
        <seg>Mặc dù đây là một con số rất cao, liệu chúng ta có thực sự nên quan tâm tới ảnh hưởng của việc tống giam tới những người đó?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>An alternative explanation for this finding could be that increased supervision during such activities prevents prisoner violence.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T171315Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T171315Z">
        <seg>Một cách lý giải khác cho điều này có thể là sự gia tăng việc kiểm soát các hành vi bạo lực của tù nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Anglo-American sentencers tend to be eclectic in their development and implementation of punishments.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151010T030520Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151010T030320Z">
        <seg>=Những người tuyên án Mỹ-Anglo có xu hướng chiết trung ( dung hòa giữa quan điểm duy tâm và duy vật) trong việc họ phát triển và thi hành hình phạt .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Another goal of imprisonment is deterrence.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T160653Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T160653Z">
        <seg>Một mục đích nữa của việc bỏ tù là để ngăn chặn việc phạm tội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As Tiersma observes, the first French &lt;t0/&gt;statute does not appear in English law until 1275, more than 200 years after the Conquest.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T143239Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T143239Z">
        <seg>Theo quan sát của Tiersma, luật của nước Pháp đầu tiên không xuất hiện trong luật nước Anh mãi tới 1275, hơn 200 năm sau cuộc xâm lăng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As a result of its general popularity, much has been written on this topic and a comprehensive review of the literature is beyond the scope of this chapter: rather we aim to give you a more accurate introduction to the topic of offender profiling.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T040214Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T030439Z">
        <seg>Như là hệ quả của sự phổ biến, rất nhiều điều đã được viết về chủ để này và một tổng kết toàn diện là nằm ngoài phạm vi của chương: thay vào đó chúng tôi muốn đưa đến bạn một  sự giới thiệu chính xác cho chủ đề thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As both disciplines move forward there is likely to be a degree of convergence in some of these areas, but the distinctions and differing interests can provide richness and perspective in a shared field of study.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T152932Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T152932Z">
        <seg>Khi cả hai ngành phát triển có thể sẽ có  mức độ hội tụ trong một số lĩnh vực, nhưng sự khác biệt và lợi ích khác nhau có thể cung cấp phong phú và quan điểm trong một lĩnh vực chia sẻ các nghiên cứu.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As mentioned above, it is clear from the research findings of the last twenty years or so that not all treatment programmes will reduce recidivism rates for all offenders, and that some programmes of rehabilitation may be more effective with certain types of offenders than with others.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151008T163328Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T162815Z">
        <seg>Như đã đề cập ở trên, những nghiên cứu trong hai mươi năm cuối rõ ràng là không phải tất cả chương trình điều trị đều sẽ giảm tỉ lệ tái phạm của tất cả người phạm tội, và với một vài chương trình cải tạo phạm nhân sẽ hiệu quả hơn khi thực hiện trên một dạng tội phạm nhất định thay vì dạng khác .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As noted above, prisoner victimization has been associated with a number of negative outcomes for prisoners.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T173414Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T173414Z">
        <seg>Như đã đề cập ở trên, sự ngược đãi đối với tù nhân đã song hành với một vài kết quả tiêu cực cho chính họ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As we saw in chapter 1, many criminal psychologists work within prisons where they will assess, manage and treat offenders in their care with the aim of reducing their likelihood of reoffending on release from prison.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T151752Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T151752Z">
        <seg>Như chúng ta đã biết trong chương 1, có rất nhiều nhà tâm lý học tội phạm làm việc trong nhà tù để tiếp cận, quản lý và chăm sóc các tù nhân nhằm giảm thiểu nguy cơ tái phạm của họ sau khi được thả ra. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As well as collecting information on adult sex offenders, twenty-eight states have a register for juvenile sex offenders and of these twenty-one release information on these offenders to the public.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T163232Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T163232Z">
        <seg>Cũng như thu thập thông tin về tội phạm tình dục trưởng thành, 28 bang có một danh sách về tội phạm tình dục thanh thiếu niên và trong đó có 21 bang công khai thông tin của những người này cho công chúng. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As well as exchanges between witness and lawyer, courtroom linguists are interested in the communication between judge and jury.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T035645Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T035313Z">
        <seg>Cũng như sự trao đổi giữa luật sư và nhân chứng,  ngôn ngữ phòng xử án quan tâm đến sự trao đổi giữa thẩm phán và bồi thẩm đoàn</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As well as giving insight into the tactics of legal examination, Ehrlich examines how the various participants in the trial have opposing conceptions of the nature of consent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T024832Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151009T092655Z">
        <seg>Cũng như đưa ra cái nhìn sâu sắc vào các chiến thuật của thi pháp luật, Ehrlich khảo sát làm thế nào những người tham gia khác nhau trong các thử nghiệm có những quan niệm đối lập về bản chất của sự đồng thuận.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As well as sometimes participating in court cases, forensic linguists also have an academic interest in the workings of the court- room.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T005446Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T005446Z">
        <seg>Trong khi tham gia các ca xử án, nhà ngôn ngữ học pháp y cũng có một quan tâm học thuật trong các công việc của các phòng xử án.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>As within most branches of psychology, there have been (and continue to be) debates concerning what constitutes the gold standard of treatment–outcome research.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151007T165143Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T165143Z">
        <seg>Vì trong nhiều phân nhánh của ngành tâm lý học, sẽ luôn tiếp tục có những cuộc tranh cãi hay mối quan tâm về việc thiết lập những chuẩn mực vàng trong nghiên cứu trị liệu-kết quả. .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>At one point I looked up and the sky was black with missiles.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T151059Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T151059Z">
        <seg>Đã có lúc tôi ngẩng lên và bầu trời đen nghịt toàn tên lửa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>At that time both police officers and the general public believed that memory was like a movie film and that what investigators needed to do was to help the witness to access such a memory.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T124031Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151009T141103Z">
        <seg>Ở thời điểm đó, cả cảnh sát lẫn công chúng đều tin rằng trí nhớ con người cũng giống như một bộ phim vậy và điều mà các nhà điều tra cần làm là giúp nhân chứng tiếp cận được mảng trí nhớ ấy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>At this point, it is important to make a distinction between sentenced and remand prisoners, and consider how their status can affect their experience of imprisonment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T164133Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T164133Z">
        <seg>Từ điểm này, ta có thể thấy việc phân biệt giữa tù nhân bị kết án và tù nhân đang được điều tra là rất quan trọng, và cần thận trọng để xem xét ... có thể ảnh hưởng tới trải nghiệm của họ khi bị giam cầm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Because male and female prisoners are held separately, imprisonment also results in the loss of heterosexual relationships.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T162401Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T162401Z">
        <seg>Bởi vì các tù nhân nam và tù nhân nữ bị giam giữ tách biệt nhau, việc này cũng sẽ dẫn đến mất đi các mối quan hệ khác giới</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Because of this, in some jurisdictions standard, legally watertight instructions have been published.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T055152Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T040522Z">
        <seg>Bởi vì điều này, trong một số quyền hạn chuẩn, hướng dẫn pháp lý chặt chẽ đã được công bố.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Before the Norman Conquest, written law appeared either in English or Latin but immediately following the Conquest all legal texts moved into Latin.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T132634Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T132634Z">
        <seg>Trước khi Norman Conquest, văn bản pháp luật viết bằng cả tiếng Anh và tiếng Latin nhưng ngay sau cuộc xâm lược của tất cả các văn bản pháp lý chuyển sang tiếng Latin.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Being at the start of a sentence.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T034827Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T034636Z">
        <seg>Đang ở giai đoạn đầu của sự thụ án.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Below is an excerpt taken from a news report from the BBC, which gives some insight into the policing experience of such an &lt;t0/&gt;event.&lt;t1/&gt; Bill King was a Chief Inspector at the time of the miners’ strike.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T144607Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T144607Z">
        <seg>Dưới đây là đoạn trích từ bài phỏng vấn tin tức của BBC, đã mang đến cái nhìn sâu hơn về trải nghiệm của cảnh sát trong những tình huống này. Bill King là Chánh Thanh tra khi cuộc tấn công của thợ mỏ xảy ra.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Beyond their normal duties police are often called in to special situations that require a coordinated response to a civilian disaster or violent incident, for example the Hillsborough Stadium disaster, the Brixton riots, or the 1980s miners’ strike.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T144411Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T142733Z">
        <seg>Ngoài những nhiệm vụ thông thường có lúc cảnh sát được gọi đến những tình huống đặc biệt cần phối hợp đối phó với thảm họa nhân loại hay sự cố bạo lực, như thảm họa Sân vận động Hillsborough, cuộc bạo loạn ở Brixton, hay cuộc tấn công của thợ mỏ những năm 1980. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Both police and citizens support the concept that effective policing requires public support, therefore to provide a professional police service the police must work with the community.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T164858Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T160749Z">
        <seg>Cả cảnh sát lẫn người dân đều ủng hộ khái niệm rằng, để việc kiểm soát an ninh trật tự được hiệu quả thì cần phải có sự hỗ trợ từ công chúng, vậy nên nhằm cung cấp một dịch vụ an ninh chuyên nghiệp, lực lượng cảnh sát phải làm việc cộng tác với dân chúng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Breaches of taboo are sexual &lt;t0/&gt;behaviours&lt;t1/&gt; that have taken place between two consenting adults but which are against the law, for example, in some states in the USA oral and anal sex are sexual offences, even if taking place in a consensual relationship.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153614Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153614Z">
        <seg>Vi phạm hình thức tình dục cấm kỵ là những hành vi tình dục giữa hai người trưởng thành tự nguyện như trái với luật pháp, ví dụ như ở một số bang ở Mỹ, tình dục bằng miệng hoặc hậu môn là xâm phạm tình dục, dù cho giữa hai người là mối quan hệ tự nguyện.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Breakfast was usually taken at about 1 a.m., so that we could be at the pits before dawn.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151008T012748Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151008T012656Z">
        <seg>Bữa sáng thường được ăn vào lúc một giờ, để sau đó chúng tôi có thể vào vị trí trước bình minh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>But how unpleasant should it be?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T161314Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T161314Z">
        <seg>Nhưng thực sự điều đó khó chịu như thế nào?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>But what is meant by criminogenic needs?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T153716Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T024544Z">
        <seg>Thế nhưng các nhu cầu dẫn đến phạm tội có nghĩa là gìã</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>But with these conflicting reports of what prison is like it is difficult to know whether we should be concerned about the 8.5 million people currently imprisoned.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152510Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152510Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, với những báo cáo trái chiều nhau như thế này, thật khó để biết rằng liệu chúng ta có nên quan tâm tới 8,5 triệu người hiện đang bị bắt giữ hay không.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Can long- term offenders become law-abiding citizens through the use of treatment programmes or do you think that an offender will always be an offender?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Nga" changedate="20151011T050941Z" creationid="Nga" creationdate="20151011T050941Z">
        <seg>Tù nhân dài hạn có thể trở thành ?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Chapter eight.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151006T161249Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151006T161249Z">
        <seg>Chương Tám</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Chapter eleven.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T153140Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T153127Z">
        <seg>Chương Mười Một</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Chapter five.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T085417Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T085417Z">
        <seg>Chương năm .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Chapter nine.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T150403Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T150403Z">
        <seg>Chương Chín.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Chapter seven.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="PhuongThao" changedate="20151009T061257Z" creationid="PhuongThao" creationdate="20151009T061257Z">
        <seg>Chapter seven</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Chapter ten.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Nga" changedate="20151006T154701Z" creationid="Nga" creationdate="20151006T154607Z">
        <seg>Chương Mười</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Chapter two.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T023922Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T023922Z">
        <seg>Chương hai.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Compared with forensic psychology, forensic linguistics is a newer and smaller discipline.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="PhuongThao" changedate="20151009T004729Z" creationid="PhuongThao" creationdate="20151009T004717Z">
        <seg>So với tâm lý học pháp y thì ngôn ngữ học pháp lý là một môn học mới và nhỏ hơn. .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Concerns about external relationships/housing.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172522Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172522Z">
        <seg>Những lo lắng về các mối quan hệ trong và ngoài gia đình.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Conclusions.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151009T143050Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151009T143050Z">
        <seg>Kết luận.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Consent might not have been given for a number of reasons.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153423Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153423Z">
        <seg>Sự đồng thuận có thể không được đưa ra vì một số lý do.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Consent, (i.e. whether the alleged rape victim agreed to have sex) is predominantly a question of communication and thus language use.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T011934Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T011934Z">
        <seg>Sự đồng thuận, (tức là nạn nhân hiếp dâm đã đồng ý quan hệ tình dục) chủ yếu là một câu hỏi của giao tiếp và  ngôn ngữ sử dụng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Consider whether there is a difference between a shoplifter who steals to feed a drug habit to one who steals to feed his or her children.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T134604Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T134604Z">
        <seg>Cân nhắc đến liệu có sự khác biệt giữa 1 tên trộm vặt trong cửa hàng để thỏa mãn thói quen dùng thuốc và 1 người ăn trộm để nuôi con của anh ta hoặc cô ta .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Conversely, the programme could have reduced the severity or frequency of an individual’s offending behaviour but the crude measure of reconviction would not detect this positive change.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151008T161340Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T160743Z">
        <seg>Trái lại, chương trình này sẽ làm giảm tính nghiêm khắc và tần số cư xử phạm tội của riêng từng người nhưng giải pháp đơn giản mà thiếu chính xác của việc tái kết án này sẽ không nhận thấy được những thay đổi tích cực.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Court cases can involve complex issues including the presentation of information that is judged to be beyond the knowledge of the average layperson who may sit on a jury.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151006T160505Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151006T155156Z">
        <seg> Các phiên tòa có thể liên quan đến các vấn đề phức tạp bao gồm nhưng thông tin không nằm trong sự hiểu biết của bồi thẩm đoàn. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Crime prevention policies always seem to be heavily influenced by media and public pressure, and sexual offending has thus become a major challenge for social policy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T160450Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T160808Z">
        <seg>Các chính sách ngăn chặn tội phạm dường như bị ảnh hưởng rất nhiều bởi áp lực truyền thông và công chúng, và lạm dụng tình dục cũng vì vậy mà trở thành một thách thức không nhỏ cho chính sách xã hội </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Criminals have to ‘pay’ for what they have done, they ‘owe a debt’ to society or a victim.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T160023Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T154837Z">
        <seg>Tội phạm phải trả cho những gì họ đã làm, họ mang 1 món nợ với xã hội hoặc với nạn nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Criminogenic needs are those that are related to the individual’s offending behaviour.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T032339Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T032339Z">
        <seg>Các nhu cầu dẫn đến phạm tội chúng đều liên quan đến hành vi phạm tội của từng cá nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Days were long and tiring, usually returning to our accommodation in the afternoons, to a hot meal and then bed, only to get up again at about midnight.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151008T012815Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151008T012740Z">
        <seg>Mỗi ngày trôi qua rất dài và mệt mỏi, chúng tôi thường về nhà vào tầm chiều, ăn một bữa nóng hổi và sau đó nằm nghỉ, để rồi lại thức dậy vào nửa đêm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Depending on the volume of prisoners being held in one institution, prisons can also be very noisy and overcrowded.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T162453Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T162453Z">
        <seg>Tùy theo mật độ người được giam giữ trong mỗi khu mà việc ở tù cũng trở nên rất ồn ào và chật chội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Despite periods of unrest, allegations of racism, sexism and awkward interactions with youths, citizens in such countries generally have trust and respect for the police.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T155416Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T154915Z">
        <seg>Mặc dù có những giai đoạn biến động, những cáo buộc về việc phân biệt chủng tộc, phân biệt giới tính và những tương tác khó khăn với thanh thiếu niên thì nhìn chung, công dân của những quốc gia này vẫn có sự tin tưởng và tôn trọng dành cho cảnh sát .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Despite this, rates of sexual offending are very much lower than for almost every other type of crime and criminal psychologists question whether our fear of sexual offending has been heightened by the constant media discussion on the topic.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T135135Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T135135Z">
        <seg>Dù thế, tỉ lệ phạm tội về tình dục thấp hơn rất nhiều so với những loại tội ác khác và các nhà tâm lý học tội phạm đặt vấn đề rằng liệu nỗi sợ của chúng ta với tội ác tình dục đã bị làm tăng lên bởi sự bàn luận về vấn đề này trên truyền thông đại chúng. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Deterring offenders from taking part in crimes, discouraging others from taking part in illegal activities, or putting criminals somewhere that they could not offend again, which will all reduce crime rates, are the key element of reductivism.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T135512Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T135512Z">
        <seg>Ngăn chặn ngững kẻ phạm tội khỏi nhúng tay vào tội ác, làm nhụt chí những tên khác khỏi tham gia các hoạt động phi pháp, hoặc đưa những tên tội phạm đến những nơi mà chúng không thể phạm tội nữa là những việc làm giảm tỉ lệ phạm tội và là yếu tố then chốt cho việc thu hẹp lại .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Developmental histories.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153711Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153711Z">
        <seg>Lịch sử phát triển.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Discussion among translators, entitled: Introduction to the Team Project feature in OmegaT.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hanthuy" changedate="20130115T115653Z">
        <seg>Thảo luận giữa những biên dịch viên, entitled: Introduction to the Team Project feature in OmegaT.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Do they stop sex offenders committing crimes once they are let out of prison?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T130925Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T130925Z">
        <seg>Liệu họ có dừng việc quấy rối tình dùng khi họ được thả khỏi tù hay không?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Do you think that it is possible to alter the behaviour of offenders?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Nga" changedate="20151011T045702Z" creationid="Nga" creationdate="20151011T045702Z">
        <seg>Bạn có nghĩ rằng phạm nhân có thể sửa đổi hành vi sau khi được tải tạo??</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>During the early 1990s in the UK, much of sentencing policy was based on this concept of deterrence, rather than the rehabilitation of offenders which became popular during the 1950s and 1960s.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T141108Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T141108Z">
        <seg>Trong suốt thời gian đầu của những năm 1900, nhiều chính sách về án phạt được dụa trên khái niệm về sự ngăn chặn này hơn là sự cải tạo của tội phạm cái mà đã trở nên phổ biến suốt những năm 1950 và 1960.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Duty during the day usually consisted of long periods of waiting, or travelling, or talking to the pickets, interspersed with short periods of violence or pushing and shoving with the pickets.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T145358Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151008T013218Z">
        <seg>Nhiệm vụ hàng ngày thường là chờ đợi, hoặc di chuyển, hoặc nói chuyện với những người biểu tình trong khoảng thời gian dài, đôi lúc còn phải sử dụng vũ lực hay xô đẩy những người biểu tình ấy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Environmental stress.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172413Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172413Z">
        <seg>Căng thẳng, áp lực từ môi trường.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Evidence of this history can be found in modern legal language.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T144111Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T144111Z">
        <seg>Bằng chứng lịch sử này có thể được tìm thấy trong ngôn ngữ pháp lý hiện đại.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Exaggerating the danger that sexual offenders pose is problematic and can increase public fear, stigmatize and hinder rehabilitation of offenders who have changed their lifestyles.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T161953Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T161953Z">
        <seg>Phóng đại sự nguy hiểm của những kẻ quấy rối tình dục thì còn phản suy xét và có thể gia tăng hoang mang trong cộng đồng, bôi bác và cản trở quá trình cải tạo của những người phạm tội đã thay đổi cách sống của mình. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Faced with cases like this it may seem that a judge or the legal system is simply being obstinate but the judge has to be cautious; there is good research to demonstrate that how the law is explained to the jury can influence its verdict.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T072520Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T072520Z">
        <seg>Đối mặt với những trường hợp như thế này có vẻ là một thẩm phán hoặc hệ thống pháp luật chỉ đơn giản là cố chấp nhưng quan tòa phải thận trọng; có nghiên cứu hay chứng minh rằng cách pháp luật được giải thích cho ban bồi thẩm có thể ảnh hưởng đến phán quyết.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Fear of violence.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172304Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172304Z">
        <seg>Nỗi sợ bị bạo hành.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Finally, offenders who are illiterate or have good reason why they would not be able to cope in a treatment group setting may need a different type of treatment programme from those who perform well in groups and can read and write adequately.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T092046Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T092046Z">
        <seg>Cuối cùng, những người phạm tội không biết chữ hoặc có lý do chính đáng tại sao họ không thể đối mặt với nhóm điều trị sẽ cần một loại chương trình điều trị khác từ những người có biểu hiện tốt trong nhóm và có thể đọc và viết một cách thỏa đáng. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For example, a profiler might try to infer a criminal’s age, gender or employment history from the way he or she has behaved during a crime.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T034603Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T034603Z">
        <seg>Ví dụ, người lập hồ sơ sẽ cố gắng suy luận tuổi, giới tính hoặc lịch sử làm việc của một tên tội phạm từ cách mà anh ta hoặc cô ta hành xử trong suốt quá trình phạm tội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For example, in many jurisdictions a jury should only convict a defendant if it believes that the case has been made against them ‘beyond reasonable doubt’.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T072957Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T072957Z">
        <seg>Ví dụ tại toà, ban bồi thẩm chỉ kết tội bị cáo nếu họ tin rằng trường hợp chống lại bị cáo là mối nghi ngờ hợp lý.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For example, in some countries within Europe, an expert witness is called by the court itself in order to provide information as and when it is needed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151007T083038Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151007T083038Z">
        <seg>Ví dụ, ở một số nước nằm trong Châu Âu, một nhân chứng chuyên gia được tòa án triệu tập để cung cấp thông tin khi cần thiết. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For example, it stands to reason that an offender who has been caught committing a residential burglary may not be responsive to a treatment programme which aims to address aggressive behaviour.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T120326Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T164121Z">
        <seg>Thí dụ, thật rõ ràng khi lí giải rằng một người phạm tội bị bắt giữ vì ăn trộm ở nhà dân có thể sẽ không được thông cảm và cho chép để tiến hành chương trình trị liệu với mục đích định vị các cư xử hung hăng. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For example, some ethnic minority groups may find it particularly difficult to talk about their criminal behaviour within a group setting.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T121004Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T093333Z">
        <seg>Ví dụ, vài nhóm dân tộc thiểu số có thể cảm thấy đặc biệt khó khăn khi nói về hành vi phạm tội của họ với nhóm thiết lập điều trị.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For example, they could be homeless, or have problems with their finances, or they may have relationship problems or substance use habits.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T030218Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T030218Z">
        <seg>Ví dụ, họ có thế không nhà, không cửa hoặc có vấn đề với tài chính, các mối quan hệ xả hội hay những thói quen bản chất.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For prison to be a punishment it must be an uncomfortable experience.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T160602Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T160602Z">
        <seg>Việc dùng làm nơi trừng phạt chẳng phải là một điều gì sung sướng đối với các nhà tù.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>For the next 200 years or so, French became the dominant language of legal texts: the main exceptions to this was in the field of Church law.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T143534Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T143534Z">
        <seg>Cho 200 năm tới hoặc lâu hơn, tiếng Pháp đã trở thành ngôn ngữ chính của các văn bản quy phạm pháp luật: các trường hợp ngoại lệ chính nằm trong các lĩnh vực giáo luật.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Forensic linguistics then is a field of research and practice which covers much ground.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T153113Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T153113Z">
        <seg>Ngôn ngữ học pháp y sau đó là một lĩnh vực nghiên cứu và thực hành trong đó bao phủ nhiều ngành.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Forum name: OmegaT support</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="itbox4vn" changedate="20130115T181128Z">
        <seg>Tên diễn đàn: OmegaT support</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>From  www.megans&lt;t0/&gt;-law.net</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T163749Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T163749Z">
        <seg>Từ www.megans-law.net</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>From the results of the meta-analyses, the panel of inter- national experts in offender rehabilitation drew up a set of criteria to which all future programmes should adhere.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T045537Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T051305Z">
        <seg>Từ kết quả của quá trình phân tích - tổng hợp, Hiệp hội chuyên gia quốc tế về cải tạo phạm nhân đã thiết lập các tiêu chí cần tuân theo đối với tất cả những chương trình trong tương lai.    </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Further investigation needs to examine the reasons for non-completion, especially within high-risk groups.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T121306Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T112340Z">
        <seg>Sau đó, công việc điều tra xa hơn cần kiểm tra lý do tại sao chưa hoàn thành, đặc biệt đối với những người trong nhóm có nguy cơ cao.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Furthermore, in &lt;t2/&gt;some  crimes&lt;t3/&gt; witnesses may not be able to see the perpetrators but can hear their voices.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T123806Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151012T123546Z">
        <seg>Hơn nữa, trong một số vụ án, có thể nhân chứng không nhìn thấy mặt nhưng lại nghe được giọng của hung thủ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Good examples include habeas corpus (the right to be taken before a court after a certain period of arrest) and &lt;t2/&gt;mens&lt;t3/&gt; rea (referring to a person’s culpable mental state with regard to a crime, e.g. intentionally harming someone or driving recklessly).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T144621Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T144621Z">
        <seg>Có thể kể đến habeas corpus (quyền được đưa ra trước một tòa án sau một thời gian bắt giữ nhất định) và mens rea (đề cập đến trạng thái tinh thần có tội của một người đối với một tội, ví dụ như cố ý làm tổn hại đến ai đó hoặc lái xe thiếu thận trọng).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Having now considered the three assumptions that underpin the practice of offender profiling, it is clearly of concern that thus far it is only the offender consistency hypothesis that shows evidence of sound empirical support.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="The sun" changedate="20151007T030330Z" creationid="The sun" creationdate="20151007T030206Z">
        <seg>Hiện tại khi cân nhắc ba giả thuyết nền tảng cho việc thực hành lập hồ sơ tâm lý tội phạm thì rõ ràng là cho tới giờ chỉ có giả thuyết về tính nhất quán của hành vi phạm tội mới đưa ra được những thông tin được chứng thực từ sự quan sát/trải nghiệm để ủng hộ cho giả thuyết.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Heffer suggests that best under- standing by the jury would be achieved if instructions were given early in a trial and involve repetition and fully relevant examples of how the legal points might be applied to the case being considered.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T071456Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T071105Z">
        <seg>Heffer gợi ý rằng bồi thẩm đoàn sẽ hiểu được tốt nhất nếu những hướng dẫn được gợi ý trước phiên toà và được lặp lại với đầy đủ ví dụ thích hợp của cách các quan điểm pháp lý được áp dụng cho trường hợp đang xem xét.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Henry VII’s defeat of Richard III at the Battle of Bosworth in 1485 brought about abrupt and sweeping legal reforms.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T143737Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T143737Z">
        <seg>Henry VII đánh bại Richard III trong trận Bosworth trong năm 1485 đã dẫn tới cải cách pháp lý đột ngột và sâu rộng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Here, we will focus on assisting witnesses/victims to identify the perpetrator by face or by voice.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T030545Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151007T020536Z">
        <seg>Ở đây, chúng tôi chú trọng vào việc giúp cho các nhân chứng/nạn nhân tìm ra thủ phạm thông qua chân dung hoặc giọng nói.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Herein lies the dilemma of the risk principle.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T105300Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T105300Z">
        <seg>Về khía cạnh tiến thoái lưỡng nan của nguyên tắc nguy cơ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Historically then, the admissibility of a psychologist’s opinion was often limited to providing evidence relating to mental impairment or the psychological functioning of an individual.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151008T164201Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151008T163112Z">
        <seg>Theo dòng lịch sử dần dần, các nhà tâm lý học được phép đưa ra ý kiến chuyên môn để cung cấp bằng chứng liên quan đến vấn đề thần kinh hay chức năng tâm lý của cá nhân  .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Homesickness.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151010T061624Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151010T061624Z">
        <seg>Nhớ nhà.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>How can the government and policy-makers make sensible, evidence-based decisions about how to deal with sex offenders, while meeting the demands of the public?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T161132Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T161132Z">
        <seg>Làm thế nào để chính phủ và các nhà lập pháp có thể đưa ra những quyết định hợp lý và có căn cứ về cách đối phó với tội phạm tình dục mà vẫn có thể đạt được những yêu cầu của công chúng?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, an alternative explanation could be that the sample size used in the research was not large enough to detect the treatment effect.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151008T052126Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T051729Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, một lý giải thay thế cho rằng kích thước mẫu thường được sử dụng trong nghiên cứu không đủ lớn để tìm ra kết quả điều trị.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, during the later 1990s another element of punishment came to the fore, that of reform or rehabilitation.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T141400Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T141400Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên vào cuối những năm 1900, 1 yếu tố khác lại giữ vị trí chủ yếu,----------  .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, even research incorporating the best methodological designs can suffer from other problems that could still result in poor quality research.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T045943Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T171356Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, kể cả những nghiên cứu kết hợp chặt chẽ với phương pháp luận tốt nhất vẫn có thể phải trải qua nhiều vấn đề khác như liệu kết quả sẽ ra sao khi chất lượng nghiên cứu không đảm bảo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, even with good procedures in place witnesses still make identification errors.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T124430Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151012T124430Z">
        <seg>Dù thế, ngay cả khi có quy trình tốt đi chăng nữa thì nhân chứng vẫn mắc lỗi.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, in England and &lt;t0/&gt;Wales&lt;t1/&gt; sexual offences account for less than one per cent of all crimes committed by young people aged ten to seventeen that actually result in them being put in a secure institution or being under the supervision of youth offending services.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T154634Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T154053Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, ở Anh và xứ Wales, con số các vụ quấy rối tình dục thấp hơn 1 phần trăm trên tổng số trường hợp phạm tội thực hiện bởi thanh niên từ 10 đến 17 tuổi và kết quả là họ được đưa vào các cơ sở bảo vệ hoặc chịu sự giám sát của những dịch vụ làm việc với tội phạm vị thành niên. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, in recent years, the psychologists’ expertise has been increasingly recognized and can now be called upon as evidence in relation to a wide variety of issues.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151008T171655Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151008T165423Z">
        <seg>Trong những năm gần đây, ý kiến về mặt chuyên môn của các nhà tâm lý học đã được nâng cao về mặt nhận thức và hiện giờ đã được nâng lên làm bằng chứng liên kết mạnh tới các vấn đề khác nhau  .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, in the UK and USA, the expert is instructed by either the &lt;t0/&gt;defence&lt;t1/&gt; or prosecution in order to provide extra strength to their version of events.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151007T083552Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151007T083552Z">
        <seg>Nhưng ở Mỹ và Anh thì nhân chứng chuyên gia sẽ nói theo chỉ thị của bên bị và bên nguyên để làm tăng thêm sức thuyết phục cho lập luật của họ. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, in what other ways can victimization impact on prisoners?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172935Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172935Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, bằng cách nào khác mà sự ngược đãi có thể ảnh hưởng đến các tù nhân?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, it must be noted that the frailties of the human mind also mean that the real perpetrators of crime may not be apprehended unless the police improve their &lt;t0/&gt;procedures in accord with the findings of relevant psychological research.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151009T143900Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151009T143650Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, cần phải lưu ý rằng những điểm yếu tồn tại trong não người cũng có nghĩa là tên tội phạm thật có thể thoát tội trừ khi phía cảnh sát hoàn thiện hơn bộ máy của họ với những phát hiện từ các nghiên cứu tâm lý có liên quan .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, reductivism is often linked to severe penalties for crimes – long prison sentences or capital punishment, which makes this form of punishment a little controversial in some people’s minds.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T135835Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T135835Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên tính thu hẹp lại lại thường liên quan đến những hình phạt khắc nghiệt - án phạt tù lâu dài hoặc án tử hình, cái mà khiến cho cách trừng phạt này hơi mang tính tranh cãi theo suy nghĩ của 1 số người </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, such retributive punishment demands that someone is to ‘blame’ for a criminal offence and considers that all offenders are equal.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T132615Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T132615Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, sự trừng phạt mang tính báo thù này lại đòi hỏi 1 người để chịu tội và coi tất cả những kẻ phạm tội là ngang nhau.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, the Home Secretary (the government minister who deals with law and order) at the time was not convinced that public access to information on the Sex Offender Register would be helpful in protecting children.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T164901Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T164714Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, Bộ Trưởng Bộ Nội Vụ (Bộ trưởng giải quyết vấn đề an ninh và trật tự) lúc ấy cảm thấy không đủ thuyết phục về việc công chúng có thể truy cập thông tin trên Danh sách Tội phạm Tình dục sẽ có ích cho bảo vệ trẻ em.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, the aims of the two processes are quite different and therefore they are discussed separately within this chapter.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T033505Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T033505Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, mục đích của hai quá trình này là hoàn toàn khác nhau và do đó chúng sẽ được thảo luận riêng biệt trong chương này.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, there are still many questions to be answered about the effectiveness of programmes and research needs to build on what we already know in order to expand knowledge of ‘What Works’.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ENVY" changedate="20151006T161603Z" creationid="ENVY" creationdate="20151006T161603Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, vẫn còn nhiều câu hỏi cần được trả lời về tính hiệu quả của các chương trình và chúng ta cần tiến hành nghiên cứu dựa trên những gì đã biết để mở rộng kiến thức về "Những hoạt động hiệu quả".</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, these judicial instructions have multiple audiences: not only are judges talking to the jury and others pre- sent in the courtroom, their words will also be examined carefully to see if there are grounds for appeal to a higher court.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T040213Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T040213Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, các hướng dẫn tư pháp có nhiều đối tượng: không chỉ là các thẩm phán nói chuyện với ban bồi thẩm và những người khác có mặt trong phòng xử, lời nói của họ cũng sẽ được kiểm tra cẩn thận để xem nếu có căn cứ để kháng cáo lên tòa án cao hơn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, this form of punishment relies on a rational thinking- offender for effect.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T140249Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T140249Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, hình thức trừng phạt này phải dựa vào những tên tội phạm có suy nghĩ lý trí thì mới có hiệu quả .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>However, years of intelligence-led policing, large amounts of paperwork, the introduction of cars and the increasing amount of specialist functions (such as fraud, Internet crime etc.) have taken the police off the street and out of the sight of the public.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T142443Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T142443Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, nhiều năm với hệ thống an ninh thông minh, lượng lớn công việc giấy tờ, sự ra đời của xe hơi và sự gia tăng số lượng các hệ thống chuyên môn (như gian lận, tội phạm Internet, v..v..) đã làm giảm tần suất cảnh sát trên đường phố và hình ảnh cảnh sát trong công chúng .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>I am sure you have seen newspaper reports stating that prison is ‘too easy’ and is more like a ‘holiday camp’ than a prison.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152255Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152255Z">
        <seg>Tôi chắc chắn rằng bạn có thể đã từng nhìn thấy một vài bài báo nói rằng nhà tù thì quá dễ dàng cho người phạm tội và nó giống như một trại nghỉ dưỡng hơn là một nhà tù thực sự.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>I felt the weight of command and concern for my officers and personal fear at the level of violence from the crowd, mixed with the excitement of the situation.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T151341Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T151341Z">
        <seg>Tôi cảm nhận được sức nặng của mệnh lệnh và sự quan tâm dành cho các sĩ quan của tôi và sự sợ hãi của bản thân trước mức độ bạo động của đám đông, trộn lẫn với sự kích động của tình hình.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>I lost a stone in weight that week and I found holes in the soles of both my shoes by the end of it.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T151758Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T151758Z">
        <seg>Tôi đã sụt mất một stone (bằng 14 pounds) và nhận thấy lỗ thủng ở cả hai đế giày khi sự cố kết thúc.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>I remember it very well: being dog tired; long, long working days; very early starts in the morning; the bitterness and understandable abuse from the crowds.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T150921Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T145637Z">
        <seg>Tôi còn nhớ rất rõ: mệt mỏi đến kiệt sức; những ngày làm việc rất dài; bắt đầu công việc từ sáng sớm;  sự cay đắng và lăng mạ có thể hiểu được từ đám đông.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If I ask ‘How are you?’ I expect different responses if I ask the question at work or at a hospital bedside and the given response depends upon shared know- ledge of what is socially appropriate.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T145734Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T145734Z">
        <seg>Nếu tôi hỏi "Anh ổn chứ?" Tôi mong đợi những phản ứng khác nhau, nếu tôi đặt câu hỏi tại nơi làm việc hoặc ở một bên giường bệnh viện và những phản ứng nhất định phụ thuộc vào chia sẻ kiến thức sâu rộng về những gì là phù hợp với xã hội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If a law is changed just to reform its language, it is very easy to slightly change its meaning or at least allow lawyers to argue for new interpretations on behalf of their clients.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T145154Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T145154Z">
        <seg>Nếu luật được thay đổi chỉ để cải cách ngôn ngữ của nó, nó là rất dễ dàng để thay đổi ý nghĩa của nó hoặc ít nhất là cho phép các luật sư biện hộ cho cách diễn giải mới thay mặt cho khách hàng của họ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If a motivation for bullying is for the bully to gain limited resources from the victim, it follows that one outcome for victims will be economic deprivation.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T171622Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T171622Z">
        <seg>Nếu động lực cho kẻ bắt nạt chỉ là để chiếm đoạt các vật phẩm hiếm từ nạn nhân thì bạc sẽ dẫn đến việc các nạn nhân bị túng thiếu về mặt tiền bạc .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If a state does not make this information available, then crime prevention funding is withheld from the state.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T163012Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T163012Z">
        <seg>Nếu bang không công khai những thông tin này thì trợ cấp phòng chống tội phạm sẽ bị rút khỏi bang. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If a twenty-year prison sentence will stop a criminal from stealing again, then so be it.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T135936Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T135936Z">
        <seg>Nếu án phạt tù 20 năm sẽ ngăn những tên tội phạm khỏi tái trộm cắp thì nó nên được thực thi .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If executing a murderer will make another person stop and think twice about carrying out a crime, then reductivism has been successful.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T140051Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T140051Z">
        <seg>Nếu việc xử tử 1 tên sát nhân sẽ làm cho 1 tên khác dừng và nghĩ lại về việc thực hiện tội ác thì chủ nghĩa thu hẹp lại đã thành công.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If someone has committed a crime, then he or she has to be punished for what he or she has done; for what has gone on in the past.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T154500Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T154500Z">
        <seg>Nếu ai dó phạm tội thì anh ta hoặc cô ta phải bị trừng phạt vì những gì anh ta/ cô ta đã lầm, vì những gì đã xảy ra trong quá khứ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If the bullies do not use these resources them- selves, they can sell them on at a higher price.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T171200Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T171023Z">
        <seg>Nếu những kẻ bắt nạt đó không sử dụng những đồ vật đó, chúng có thể bán với một cái giá cao hơn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If the burglar does not display aggressive behaviour, or if aggressive behaviour does not relate to his or her offending behaviour, then a programme with aggression as its main treatment target is not going to equip the burglar with the necessary skills to stop burgling homes.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T120349Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T165614Z">
        <seg>Nếu tên trộm không bộc lộ thái độ hung hăng hoặc nếu biểu hiện hung mãn đó không liên quan đến cách cư xử của hắn, rồi có một chương trình với mục đích chính sẽ không phải là trang bị cho tên trộm những kĩ năng cần thiết để ngừng trộm đồ trong nhà. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If the offenders are assessed as being at ‘high risk’ of reoffending, then schools, community groups and members of the public, such as &lt;t2/&gt;neighbours&lt;t3/&gt;, will be notified.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T165830Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T165233Z">
        <seg>Nếu các tội phạm bị đánh giá là khả năng tái phạm ở mức "nguy hiểm cao", thì các trường học, cộng đồng và quần chúng như hàng xóm sẽ được thông báo. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If the offenders are assessed as being ‘medium risk’ of reoffending, then schools and community groups that may encounter those offenders will be notified.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T165533Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T164645Z">
        <seg>Nếu những tội phạm đó bị đánh giá là khả năng tái phạm ở mức "nguy hiểm trung bình", thì các trường học và cộng đồng có liên quan đến những người này đều sẽ được thông báo. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If the standard of the research is poor, then the conclusions may be incorrect and our knowledge base will contain errors.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T115238Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T164632Z">
        <seg>Nếu tiêu chuẩn của công trình nghiên cứu còn hạn chế, thì phần kết luận có thế sẽ thiếu chính xác và kiến thức nền tảng của chúng ta sẽ chứa nhiều sai sót.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If the threat of imprisonment is to deter prisoners from reoffending or to deter otherwise law-abiding citizens from committing crime, imprisonment must be an unpleasant experience.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T161325Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T161209Z">
        <seg>Nếu như mục đích của việc bắt giữ là để ngăn cản những người bị giam giữ khỏi nguy cơ tái phạm hoặc để ngăn ngừa các hành động phạm pháp của những công dân tuân thủ pháp luật, việc bỏ tù chắc hẳn cũng không phải là một trải nghiệm vui thú.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If you have actually read such a contract you may have noticed that it is difficult to understand.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131801Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131801Z">
        <seg>Nếu bạn thực sự đọc một hợp đồng như vậy bạn sẽ thấy nó rất khó hiểu.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>If you have ever signed any kind of contract whether for a credit card, a telephone or a property rental agreement you will have encountered legal language.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131712Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131712Z">
        <seg>Nếu bạn đã từng ký vào bất kỳ loại hợp đồng nào đó cho dù một thẻ tín dụng, điện thoại hay hợp đồng thuê tài sản bạn sẽ gặp ngôn ngữ pháp lý.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In Anglo-Saxon England, the aim of punishment for crime was to stop physical retaliation by victims’ families.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T151837Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T151837Z">
        <seg>Ở Anglo-Saxon Anh, mục đích của việc trừng trị tội ác là để ngăn chặn sự trả thù về thể chất từ gia đình nạn nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In Britain there are often calls for more uniformed police on the street, which research suggests offers citizens reassurance, lowers fear of crime and maintains law and order.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T165439Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T165439Z">
        <seg>Ở Anh thường có những đề nghị cho việc tăng số lượng cảnh sát mặc quân phục trên đường phố, điều mà thông qua khảo sát cho thấy có thể cung cấp cho người dân sự an tâm, giữ sự sợ hãi tội phạm ở mức độ thấp nhất và duy trì luật lệ cũng như trật tự.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In England and Wales in the period 2004–5 there were 60,000 sexual crimes recorded by the police.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T160430Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T134027Z">
        <seg>Ở Anh và xứ Wales vào khoảng thời gian từ 2004 đến 2005, có 60,000 tội ác tình dục được ghi nhận bởi cảnh sát.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In England and Wales the Gay Police &lt;t0/&gt;Association was set up in 1990.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151006T193257Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151006T193257Z">
        <seg>Ở Anh và xứ Wales Hiệp hội Cảnh sát Đồng tính được thành lập năm 1990.&lt;t0/&gt;</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In a recent evaluation of community-based offending behaviour programmes carried out by the Universities of Leicester and Liverpool in the UK, those offenders who failed to complete programmes and those who failed even to start the programmes were the very people who are judged by the risk principle to be in greater need of treatment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T153603Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T110637Z">
        <seg>Trong bản đánh giá của chương trình khảo sát hành vi phạm tội ở cộng đồng được thực hiện bởi trường Đại học Leicester và Đại học Liverpool của Anh Quốc, những phạm nhân không thể hoàn thành chương trình và thậm chí không thể bắt đầu chương trình đều được đánh giá bằng nguyên tắc nguy cơ, và tất cả họ đều thật sự cần giải pháp điều trị tốt hơn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In addition to these responsibilities, prison psychologists also conduct research related to imprisonment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T151808Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T151808Z">
        <seg>Ngoài ra, các nhà tâm lý tội phạm cũng tiến hành các nghiên cứu liên quan đến vấn đề  giam giữ tù nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In addition, it could be that both individuals have tried to stop their problem behaviour but, while they may have managed to do so for a short time, eventually they have lapsed back into their old habits.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151011T150146Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151011T145945Z">
        <seg>Hơn nữa, các cá nhân đã cố gắng ngăn cản vấn đề về hành vi của họ nhưng khi họ có thể xoay sở trong một thời gian ngắn, rốt cuộc thì họ lại quay về với thói quen cũ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In contrast, there have been numerous documentaries and television series which have shown a more unpleasant and distressing side to imprisonment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152406Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152406Z">
        <seg>Nhưng ngược lại, cũng có vô số các tài liệu và chương trình truyền hình đã phản ánh các khía cạnh không tốt đẹp và đầy đau khổ của việc giam giữ .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In contrast, those offenders who are high risk need some form of intervention in order to prevent future criminal behaviour.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T104652Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T104550Z">
        <seg>Trái lại, những người phạm tội có nguy cơ tái phạm cao cần một vài hình thức can thiệp để ngăn ngừa hành vi phạm tội trong tương lai. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In fact in many countries the private security industry has developed its services at a staggering rate and conducts a diverse range of activities.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T150219Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T150219Z">
        <seg>Trên thực tế, ở nhiều quốc gia, ngành công nghiệp an ninh tư nhân đã phát triển những dịch vụ của chúng một cách nhanh chóng và có thể đảm nhiệm đa dạng các hoạt động khác nhau.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In many countries, but not yet all, it is now recognized that showing a witness just one face (e.g. using a photograph or the actual suspect him/herself – the latter is called a ‘show-up’) and asking if this is the perpetrator is not a good procedure.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T123236Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151007T022011Z">
        <seg>Tại nhiều nước, tuy chưa phải tất cả, đã công nhận việc chỉ cho nhân chứng thấy một khuôn mặt ( như dùng một tấm ảnh hoặc chính nghi phạm thật - cái sau được gọi là "sự lộ diện") và hỏi họ đây có phải thủ phạm hay không không phải là một cách làm đúng đắn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In many crimes the perpetrators speak and therefore might later be identified by &lt;t0/&gt;earwitnesses&lt;t1/&gt;.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T123751Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151012T123612Z">
        <seg>In many crimes the perpetrators speak and therefore might later be identified by &lt;t0/&gt;earwitnesses&lt;t1/&gt;</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In order for smokers to give up smoking they will need to look at what is contributing to their continuing habit.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T044356Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T044356Z">
        <seg>Để người hút thuốc lá từ bỏ hút thuốc, họ sẽ cần quan sát điều gì đã góp phần vào việc tiếp tục thói quen xấu đó.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In order for treatment to reach its maximum effectiveness, it should be appropriate for those individuals in attendance.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T102610Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T102610Z">
        <seg>Để kết quả điều trị đạt hiệu quả tối đa cần trị liệu riêng từng cá nhân. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In order to facilitate this process in England and Wales (and now in other countries, such as Australia, which have since followed suit and developed similar systems to the one described here), the government’s Crime Reduction Programme provided funding not only for the development of programmes, but also for the establishment of an accreditation system for these programmes.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151007T042358Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T041904Z">
        <seg>Để tạo điều kiện cho quá trình này ở Anh Quốc và xứ Wales (hiện tại là ở những quốc gia khác như Australia đã đi theo con đường này và phát triển nhiều hệ thống tương tự với quá trình được mô tả ở đây), Chương Trình Giảm Thiểu Tội Ác của chính phủ đã cung cấp ngân quỹ không những cho sự phát triển của chương trình mà còn thiết lập một hệ thống chứng nhận cho chúng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In recent years commercialism has grown, and so has the need for shop owners to protect the premises against shoplifters and trouble makers.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T145528Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T145528Z">
        <seg>Trong những năm gần đây chủ nghĩa trọng thương đã lớn mạnh, và kéo theo đó là sự gia tăng nhu cầu của các chủ cửa hàng trong việc bảo vệ khu vực kinh doanh của mình khỏi những kẻ trộm cắp và những thành phần gây rối.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In some prisons, the front of a cell is composed of open bars which denies the prisoner any privacy at all.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T162840Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T162840Z">
        <seg>Ở một số nhà tù, trước cửa phòng giam sẽ có một quán bars. Điều này sẽ khiến cho tù nhân hoàn toàn không còn sự riêng tư.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In such situations, the court permits the calling of an expert witness who, by definition, has an expertise relating to the issue in question.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151007T081818Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151007T081818Z">
        <seg> Trong những trường hợp như thế, tòa án sẽ cho phép gọi một nhân chứng chuyên gia nghĩa là người có chuyên môn liên quan đến các vấn đề phức tạp như đã nó ở trên.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In the UK Chris Heffer argues that jury instructions should be seen as a teaching exercise.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T063137Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T063137Z">
        <seg>Tại Anh, Chris Heffer cho rằng hướng dẫn của ban bồi thẩm nên được coi như là một bài giảng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In the UK a campaign for a similar law came from the News of the World newspaper and the parents of Sarah Payne, who was killed in 2001.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T163914Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T163914Z">
        <seg>Ở Vương quốc Anh, một chiến dịch cho điều luật tương tự bắt đầu từ báo News of the World và phụ huynh của Sarah Payne - em bé bị giết năm 2001</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In the UK, the Sexual Offences Act 2003 includes substantial increases in sentence length for many sexual offences and increased management of offenders for up to ten years after a sentence has been spent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153327Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T170146Z">
        <seg>Ở Vương quốc Anh, Đạo luật về Xâm phạm tình dục 2003 bao gồm việc tăng đáng kể trong độ dài bản án dành cho nhiều tội phạm tình dục và tăng thời gian quản thúc tội phạm lên đến 10 năm sau khi thi hành án.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In the USA, such concerns led to Megan’s Law in 1996, which allows private and personal information on those registered as sex offenders against children, to be made available to the community (see the box on the previous pages for more information).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T140137Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T170126Z">
        <seg>Ở Mỹ,  những mối quan tâm như thế này đã dẫn đến Luật Megan vào năm 1996, luật này cho phép thông tin riêng tư và cá nhân của những kẻ quấy rối tình dục ở trẻ em được công khai đến cộng đồng (tham khảo khung ở trang trước để biết thêm thông tin).  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In the USA, the country that puts more of its population in prison than any other country in the world, almost one quarter of the state prison populations are sex offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T134833Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T134833Z">
        <seg>Ở Mỹ, đất nước giam giữ dân của mình trong tù nhiều hơn bất kì nước nào trên thế giới, gần như một phần ba tội phạm của nhà tù bang là tội phạm tình dục.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In the sixteenth century a London writer, Robert Greene, noted that crime was becoming like entertainment and this meant that more and more often reports of offences and their punishments were appearing in newspapers, journals and chronicles.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T152551Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T152551Z">
        <seg>Vào thế kỷ 16, 1 nhà văn Luân-đôn, Robert Greene, ghi nhận rằng tội ác đang trở thành 1 sự giải trí và điều này có nghĩa là ngày càng nhiều những báo cáo về việc xúc phạm và sự trừng phạt của chúng xuất hiện trên báo chí, tạp chí và tin vặt.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In their efforts to understand and provide explanations for the difficulties of legal language, linguists have come up with two main answers.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131935Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131935Z">
        <seg>Trong những nỗ lực của họ để hiểu và đưa ra giải thích cho những khó khăn của ngôn ngữ pháp lý, ngôn ngữ học đã đưa ra hai câu trả lời chính.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In their search for reform, linguists have not only studied the nature of legal language but also tried to understand why legal language is as it is.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131913Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131913Z">
        <seg>Trong khi đi tìm cho cải cách, ngôn ngữ học đã không chỉ nghiên cứu các tính chất của ngôn ngữ pháp lý mà còn cố gắng tìm hiểu lý do tại sao ngôn ngữ pháp lý là như vậy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In this section we will look first at the beliefs and then at the reality.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T095520Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T095520Z">
        <seg>Trong phần này , chúng ta trước tiên sẽ xem xét về những niềm tin và sau đó là nhìn vào thực tế</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>In this sense, our knowledge about what constitutes an effective intervention can only ever be as good as the standard of research that is conducted in this area.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T115215Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T150344Z">
        <seg>Trong trường hợp này, kiến thức của chúng ta về việc thiết lập quá trình can thiệp hiệu quả có thể tốt như tiêu chuẩn của nghiên cứu được thực hiện trong phạm vi này.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Indeed, some of this extra recall turned out to be correct and so the police concluded that it was due to the hypnosis, ignoring the possibility that it could have been due to other factors necessary for hypnosis (e.g. a quiet, uninterrupted room and a relaxed, focused witness).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151009T143001Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151009T143001Z">
        <seg>Thật vậy, some of this extra recall turned out to be correct and so the police concluded that it was due to the hypnosis, ignoring the possibility that it could have been due to other factors necessary for hypnosis (e.g. a quiet, uninterrupted room and a relaxed, focused witness).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Instead, they sometimes allow an expert witness (such as myself) to testify (e.g. inform the jury) (&lt;t4/&gt;i&lt;t5/&gt;) about research findings on the general reliability of &lt;t6/&gt;earwitnessing&lt;t7/&gt; (such as that mentioned above) and (ii) on factors directly relevant to the ear- witness evidence being presented in that particular trial.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T123401Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151012T123401Z">
        <seg>Thay vào đó, they sometimes allow an expert witness (such as myself) to testify (e.g. inform the jury) (&lt;t4/&gt;i&lt;t5/&gt;) about research findings on the general reliability of &lt;t6/&gt;earwitnessing&lt;t7/&gt; (such as that mentioned above) and (ii) on factors directly relevant to the ear- witness evidence being presented in that particular trial.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Introduction to the Team Project feature in OmegaT (OmegaT support)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hanthuy" changedate="20130115T115538Z">
        <seg>Giới thiệu tính năng làm việc nhóm trong OmegaT (hỗ trợ OmegaT)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Introduction.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="PhuongThao" changedate="20151009T061308Z" creationid="PhuongThao" creationdate="20151009T004631Z">
        <seg>Giới thiệu.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It assumes that an offender will weigh up the pros and cons of committing a crime, decide that the punishment is not worth the gain from the crime and decide not to steal, vandalize, or kill.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T140619Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T140619Z">
        <seg>Chúng ta kết luận rằng 1 tên tội phạm sẽ cân nhắc được và mất từ việc phạm tội, quyết định rằng hình phạt đó không đáng với những gì có được từ tội ác đó và quyết định không ăn trộm, phá hoại hoặc giết chóc nữa .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It can be argued that although the law has been reformed, the courtroom exchanges reveal that the ideology it reflected still existed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T034951Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T034951Z">
        <seg>Mặc dù luật pháp đã được cải cách, các phiên toà cho thấy các ý tưởng ngược lại vẫn tồn tại.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It can further be argued that society’s wider attitudes to sexual &lt;t0/&gt;behaviour&lt;t1/&gt; and relationships between the sexes can all be examined through the microcosm of a rape trial.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T013404Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T013404Z">
        <seg>Nó có thể được lập luận rằng quan điểm xã hội phổ biến về hành vi tình dục và mối liên quan đến giới tính có thể kiểm tra qua phiên toà xét xử hiếp dâm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It can take many forms, such as psycho- logical, financial, emotional or physical suffering.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151006T162750Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151006T162206Z">
        <seg>Có thể có nhiều dạng như nhứng đau đớn, khổ sở về thể chất, tinh thần, tài chính và logic thần kinh  .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It could be that both the smoker and the criminal see that their behaviour is having a detrimental effect on their lives and the lives of their loved ones.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T035241Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T035107Z">
        <seg>Giá như cả người hút thuốc lá và tên tội phạm nhận thức được hành vi của họ có tác động bất lợi đến cuộc sống và những người thân yêu xung quanh họ. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It could be that their partner also smokes and encourages them to continue smoking or it could be that they use smoking as a way of controlling their weight by having a cigarette instead of eating.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T045628Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T044812Z">
        <seg>Khi người đồng hành với họ cũng hút thuốc và còn động viên họ tiếp tục hút hoặc khi họ dùng thói quen hút thuốc như là một cách để kiểm soát cân nặng thay vì ăn uống.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It has also been suggested that bullying might offer relief from tension and boredom.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151010T090406Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151010T090406Z">
        <seg>Cũng có người cho rằng việc bắt nạt có thể khiến ta giải toả bớt những căng thẳng và chán nản.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is an offence that seems to be more than just a crime; it is regarded as a social and health problem and is frequently reported in newspapers and on the television and radio.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T131342Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T131342Z">
        <seg>Nó không chỉ là một tội ác; mà còn được xem như một vấn đề xã hội và sức khoẻ và thường xuyên được đề cập đến trên báo chí, trên tivi và radio.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is argued that the process and in particular the opposing lawyers can create a very negative experience for the woman which can amount to re-victimization.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T012907Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T012646Z">
        <seg>Có ý kiến cho rằng quá trình này và đặc biệt là các luật sư đối lập có thể tạo ra một trải nghiệm rất tiêu cực đối với người phụ nữ mà có thể một số là tái nạn nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is clear that media reporting of sexual offending is often distorted, for example, giving the impression that young women are very likely to be sexually attacked on the way home from a night out, or that young boys will be abused by strangers.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T160501Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T161438Z">
        <seg>Rõ ràng là việc trình báo trên truyền thông về quấy rối tình dục thường bị bóp méo, ví dụ như mặc định rằng những phụ nữ trẻ thường dễ bị tấn công trên đường về nhà khi ra ngoài vào buổi tối, hoặc các cậu trai trẻ sẽ bị lạm dụng bởi người lạ.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is for this reason that the punishment of crime becomes such a moral dilemma: bringing about debate as to who should have the right to punish others, who decides what is punishable and what is not, and what form punishment should take.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151006T163633Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151006T163143Z">
        <seg>Chính vì lý do này mà việc trừng phạt tội phạm trở thành 1 tình thế khó xử về đạo đức: nó gây ra những cuộc tranh luận như ai là người có quyền trừng phạt người khác, ai có thể quyết định cái gì đáng bị trừng phạt và cái nào không, và nên sử dụng hình thức trừng phạt nào.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is often the case that offenders have problematic issues in many areas of their lives that need resolution in order to aid their desistence from crime.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T025801Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T024905Z">
        <seg>Trong trường hợp những người phạm tội có nhiều vấn đề trong cuộc sống của họ và họ cần được hỗ trợ để ngăn cản ý định phạm tội. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is therefore quite easy to understand why the prison environment itself can result in prisoners experiencing stress.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T163322Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T163322Z">
        <seg>Vì vậy cũng khá dễ hiểu tại sao môi trường nhà tù tự thân nó đã khiến cho các tù nhân thấy stress.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is these criminogenic needs that the treatment programme should address in order to attempt to alter the behaviour of those in attendance.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T150710Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T144531Z">
        <seg>Những nhu cầu dẫn đến phạm tội của chương trình điều trị nên được bàn đến để nỗ lực thay đổi hành vi của những người tham gia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is these problems or issues that contribute to the individuals continuing in their pattern of criminal behaviour.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T032744Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T032744Z">
        <seg>Những vấn đề này góp phần xây dựng một điển hình về hành vi phạm tội của các cá nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It is very difficult to give a full and complete definition of a sexual offender – examples might include someone who has committed a sexual offence, someone who has been convicted of a sexual offence or someone who has committed a sexual act without the consent of the other person.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153405Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153405Z">
        <seg>Rất khó để có thể định nghĩa đầy đủ và chính xác một tội phạm tình dục - các hình mẫu có thể bao gồm một người đã có hành vi quấy rối tình dục, một người đã bị kết án là quấy rối tình dục hoặc một người thực hiện thành động quấy rối mà không có sự đồng thuận từ người khác.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It requires precision and understanding to be stable across situation and time.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T150958Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T150958Z">
        <seg>Nó đòi hỏi độ chính xác và sự hiểu biết để ổn định trạng thái qua thời gian.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It seems that some sort of monetary compensation for loss was preferable to a physical punishment, and only repeat offenders were punished by having part of their body removed or injured in some manner.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T152159Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T152159Z">
        <seg>Dường như cách đền bù mất mát bằng tiền bạc này là thích hợp hơn so với sự trừng phạt về thể xác và chỉ có những kẻ tái phạm nhiều lần mới bị trừng phạt bằng việc cắt rời bộ phận cơ thể hoặc làm cho bị thương theo 1 số phong tục  .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>It will also introduce you to the equally fascinating but relatively unpublicized practice of linking crimes, which has at times been considered a type of offender profiling.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T035600Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T031632Z">
        <seg>Chương hai này cũng sẽ giới thiệu với các bạn hoạt động rất thú vị nhưng hầu như chưa được công khai của việc xâu chuỗi các tội ác, điều mà đôi khi được xem như là một dạng của thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Its recent appearances in the media have certainly raised the profile of criminal psychology and a number of students are keen to work in this area.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T024951Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T024951Z">
        <seg>Gần đây, thuật ngữ này được xuất hiện trên các phương tiện truyền thông đã thúc đẩy hồ sơ của tâm lý học tội phạm và số lượng học sinh mong muốn làm việc trong lĩnh vực này.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Just as crimes have changed, so too have punishments.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T151111Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T151111Z">
        <seg>Giống như việc tội ác thay đổi thì sự trừng phạt cũng thế.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Just as smokers need to work out what it is about their circumstances that prevent them from giving up cigarettes, it is necessary for offenders and their case managers to assess what circumstances or issues within their lives are likely &lt;t0/&gt;to  be&lt;t1/&gt;  contributing  to  the continuation of their offending behaviour.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T150659Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T045802Z">
        <seg>Cũng như những người hút thuốc cần hiểu vì sao hoàn cảnh của họ khiến họ không thể từ bỏ thói quen hút thuốc, những phạm nhân và các nhà quản lý cũng cần đánh giá hoàn cảnh nào hay các vấn đề trong cuộc sống của họ có khả năng góp phần vào việc tiếp diễn các hành vi phạm tội.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Just as the risk and need principles state that the offenders’ risk and need status should be considered in the design of programmes and the allocation of offenders to them, the responsivity principle states that treatment programmes and the delivery of them should be geared to the offenders’ abilities and learning styles.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ENVY" changedate="20151008T104824Z" creationid="ENVY" creationdate="20151008T104744Z">
        <seg>Các nguyên tắc về nguy cơ và nhu cầu phát biểu rằng các đặc điểm về nguy cơ và nhu cầu (của phạm nhân) cần được xem xét khi thiết kế và phân chia phạm nhân vào các chương trình. Tương tự, nguyên tắc đáp ứng cho rằng các chương trình điều trị và việc phân phối chúng cần phù hợp với khả năng và cách học của phạm nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Just being imprisoned results in a loss of freedom and a loss of autonomy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T161955Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T161955Z">
        <seg>Chỉ riêng việc bị nhốt cũng đã khiến người bị giam giữ mất đi tự do và quyền tự quyết </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Large-scale research projects are needed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T115709Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T052614Z">
        <seg>Thay vào đó, những dự án nghiên cứu quy mô lớn lúc này thực sự rất cần thiết.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Latin vocabulary and structures are also found.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T144426Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T144426Z">
        <seg>Từ điển và cấu trúc tiếng Latin cũng được tìm thấy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Lawrence Solan charted some of these variations, ranging from ‘actual and substantial doubt’, and ‘not a mere possible doubt’, to ‘not a conjecture or fanciful doubt’ and ‘abiding conviction of guilt’.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T073313Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T073313Z">
        <seg>Lawrence Solan xếp một số các biến thể khác nhau, từ 'nghi ngờ thực tế và đáng kể', và 'không phải là chỉ có thể nghi ngờ', đến 'không phải là một sự phỏng đoán và nghi ngờ huyền ảo "và" tuân thủ pháp kết án tội lỗi'.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Legal language, especially the language of contracts, cannot be like this.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T150116Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T150116Z">
        <seg>Ngôn ngữ pháp lý, đặc biệt là ngôn ngữ của hợp đồng, không thể được như vậy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Likewise, female offenders may require different types of programmes from male offenders, and the needs of ethnic minority groups may again be different.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T092436Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T092436Z">
        <seg>Tương tự, đối với tội phạm nữ đòi hỏi những dạng chương trình khác so với tội phạm là nam, và yêu cầu đối với nhóm tội phạm là dân tộc thiểu số lại càng khác hơn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Linguists have recently argued for and been involved in attempts to reform these instructions to answer the needs of both audiences.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T063016Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T063016Z">
        <seg>Ngôn ngữ học mới đây đã tranh luận và được tham gia vào các nỗ lực cải cách các hướng dẫn để đáp ứng nhu cầu của mọi người.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Longer sentences.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T034616Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T034616Z">
        <seg>Bản án lâu hơn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>MEGAN’S LAW AND THE CAMPAIGN FOR SARAH’S LAW.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T162021Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T162021Z">
        <seg>Luật Megan và chiến dịnh cho Luật Sarah.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Male gender.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T034359Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T034359Z">
        <seg>Giới tính là nam.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Males account for ninety-eight per cent of convicted sexual offenders (Youth Justice Board, 2004).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T154950Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T154950Z">
        <seg>Nam giới chiếm khoảng 98% trong cách cáo buộc về quấy rối tình dục (theo Hội Đồng công lý thanh thiếu niên, 2004).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Many people have an inadequate appreciation of what hypnosis actually involves and what its limitations are.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151009T140837Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151009T140837Z">
        <seg>Nhiều người không hiểu đúng về những gì thôi miên có thể làm và cả những giới hạn của nó.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Many writers believe that it is the notion of ‘policing by consent’ that is the hallmark of British policing.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T162233Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T162233Z">
        <seg>Khá nhiều tác giả cho rằng đây là quan niệm về "kiểm soát thông qua sự đồng thuận", đó chính là tiêu chuẩn của lực lượng an ninh Anh quốc.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Megan &lt;t0/&gt;Kanka&lt;t1/&gt; was a seven-year-old girl who was raped and murdered by a convicted sex offender in 1994 in New Jersey, USA.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T163532Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T162414Z">
        <seg>Megan Kanka là một cô bé 7 tuổi, bị cưỡng hiếp và sát hại bởi một kẻ quấy rối tình dục vào năm 1994 ở New Jersey, Mỹ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>More than fifty years ago some police forces (e.g. in the USA) began to use hypnosis in attempts to assist witnesses recall more of what they had experienced.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151009T141207Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151009T141051Z">
        <seg>Từ hơn năm mươi năm trước, nhiều lực lượng cảnh sát (như Mĩ) đã bắt đầu dùng thôi miên nhằm gợi cho nhân chứng nhớ lại được nhiều hơn về những điều họ từng trải qua.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Most criminal psychologists now seem to be of the opinion that ‘evidence’ obtained under hypnosis should not be allowed in court.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T124210Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151012T124155Z">
        <seg>Số đông các nhà tâm lý học tội phạm phản đối việc sử dụng những "bằng chứng" có được dưới ảnh hưởng của thôi miên khi xét xử.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Most language depends on the wider context to be understood.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T145516Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T145516Z">
        <seg>Hầu hết các ngôn ngữ phụ thuộc vào bối cảnh rộng lớn hơn để được hiểu rõ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Most research in this area uses reconviction (either ‘reconvicted’ or ‘not reconvicted’) as the measure by which treatment success or failure is evaluated.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T115924Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T154011Z">
        <seg>Hầu hết nghiên cứu gần đây đều dùng sự tái kết án (kết án lại hoặc không) như là giải pháp để đánh giá thành công hay thất bại của việc điều trị.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Much of the eyewitness research conducted by psychologists has focused on making identification procedures as fair as possible (to the suspect/the accused).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151007T013812Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151007T013812Z">
        <seg>Đã có nhiều nghiên cứu về nhân chứng được các nhà tâm lý học thực hiện tập trung vào việc làm cho quá trình nhận diện được diễn ra một cách công bằng nhất.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Much of the punishment described above is based on retribution.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T153704Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T153704Z">
        <seg>Nhiều hình phạt được đề cập ở trên là dựa trên sự đền bù, báo thù </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Much of this research has been conducted in the West: its findings might not apply so readily to prisons in other parts of the world and it is important to bear this in mind.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152555Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152555Z">
        <seg>Phần lớn nghiên cứu này được tiến hành ở phương Tây: những phát hiện có thể không dễ dàng áp dụng vào các nhà tù ở những nơi khác trên thế giới và cần phải ghi nhớ điều quan trọng này.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Now, most people would wince at the thought of punishing someone for blasphemy by tying them to a piece of fencing and dragging them through the streets of the local town, but they may still find the death penalty acceptable, or would think that a community-based penalty for non-payment of a fine is an appropriate punishment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T151515Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T151515Z">
        <seg>Ngày nay, nhiều người sẽ rụt rè trước suy nghĩ trừng phạt ai đó vì tội báng bổ bằng cách trói học vào 1 mảnh hàng rào và kéo họ đi khắp các con phố trong thị trấn, nhưng họ có thể vẫn thấy rằng án tử hình là có thể chấp nhận được hoặc nghĩ rằng lao động công ích vì trốn vé phạt là 1 hình phạt thích đáng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Offender profiling is the inferring of an offender’s characteristics from his or her crime scene behaviour.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T033929Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T033929Z">
        <seg>Lập hồ sơ tội phạm là sự suy luận về những đặc tính của tội phạm từ hành vi của anh ta hay cô ta tại hiện trường tội ác.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Offender profiling is typically used with crimes where the offender’s identity is unknown and with serious types of crime, such as murder or rape.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T035208Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T035208Z">
        <seg>Việc thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm thường được sử dụng với những tội ác mà chưa biết danh tính của tội phạm và những loại tội ác nguy hiểm ví dụ như giết người hoặc cưỡng hiếp .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Offenders may have low levels of educational ability or have problems getting and holding onto employment, or it may be that their associates (family and friends) are involved in crime.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T153748Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T030522Z">
        <seg>Những người phạm tội có trình độ học vấn thấp hay có những vấn đề về công việc như bị sa thải hay những người thân của họ dính líu đến tội ác nào đó. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Offenders, then, can often present for treatment with a whole host of issues, or needs, that require addressing.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T153816Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T031839Z">
        <seg>Và rồi họ sẽ có thể bộc lộ toàn bộ vấn đề, nhu cầu hoặc điều mà họ đang ngắm tới đễ phục vụ cho quá trình điều trị.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>On the other hand there is very little linguistic work on offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T151955Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T151955Z">
        <seg>Mặt khác có rất ít công trình ngôn ngữ học về những người phạm tội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Once this evidence is available it will then fall to treatment services to ensure that their provision is adapted in line with these findings in order to achieve maximum levels of treatment completion.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T113011Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T113011Z">
        <seg>Khi mà chứng cứ có sẵn, chúng sẽ được giao cho dịch vụ điều trị để đảm bảo rằng nguồn cung cấp của họ được chỉnh sửa lại sao cho phù hợp với kết quả điều tra, để đạt được cấp độ cao nhất của vệc hoàn thành điều trị.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>One area which has been well examined is that of rape trials.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T010932Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T010932Z">
        <seg>Phiên tòa xét xử hiếp dâm là một nơi làm minh hoạ tốt.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>One example of a linguistic analysis of rape trials is Susan Ehrlich’s (2001) work.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T013609Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T013609Z">
        <seg>Một ví dụ của phân tích ngôn ngữ của xét xử hiếp dâm là nghiên cứu của Susan Ehrlich (2001)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>One further argument for their maintenance is that the operation of the law requires stability of linguistic meanings.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T145029Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T145029Z">
        <seg>Một ý kiến khác của cuộc thảo luận là sự vận hành của luật pháp đòi hỏi sự ổn định của ý nghĩa của ngôn ngữ học.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>One of the judges’ tasks in UK and US trials is to explain the law to juries so that they can apply the evidence of the case to come to their verdict.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T040014Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T040014Z">
        <seg>Một trong những nhiệm vụ của thẩm phán trong phiên toàn ở nước Anh và Mỹ là để giải thích luật cho ban bồi thẩm để họ áp dụng chứng cứ của vụ án vào phán quyết.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>One recent success in linguistic reform of the legal system has been Peter Tiersma’s work with the Californian Judicial Council which in August 2005 agreed new plain language jury instructions.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T073808Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T073808Z">
        <seg>Một thành công gần đây trong cải cách về ngôn ngữ của hệ thống pháp luật nhờ nghiên cứu của Peter Tiersma với Hội đồng Tư pháp California trong Tháng Tám năm 2005 đã đồng ý hướng dẫn bồi thẩm đoàn bằng ngôn ngữ đơn giản mới.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>One very relevant issue is how witnesses are questioned/inter- viewed, which was covered in chapter 4.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151010T071126Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151007T015912Z">
        <seg>Có một vấn đề liên quan, đó là cách các nhân chứng được hỏi/phỏng vấn, đã được trình bày ở chương 4.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Only programmes that met these criteria were to be adopted and implemented by the Prisons and Probation Service for delivery to the offenders under their supervision.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T152957Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T144520Z">
        <seg>Những chương trình này gồm những tiêu chí được thông qua và thi hành bởi Cơ quan quản lý nhà tù và giám sát phạm nhân với mục đích là để giám sát những người phạm tội. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Other research has shown that one in four women have been subject to a sexual assault or rape.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T133856Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T133856Z">
        <seg>Một nghiên cứu khác đã chỉ ra rằng cứ 4 phụ nữ thì có 1 người đã từng là nạn nhân của cưỡng hiếp hoặc cưỡng dâm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Over a period of time Norman French became established in England as the language of the ruling class and gradually filtered through to the language of the law.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T142912Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T142912Z">
        <seg>Trong thời kì của Norman tiếng Pháp là ngôn ngữ ở Anh như là ngôn ngữ của giai cấp thống trị và chọn lọc trở thành ngôn ngữ của pháp luật.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Over the last fifty years or so there has been a massive increase in the amount of land, property and possessions that citizens own (and many of these possessions such as DVD players, laptops, mobile phones and televisions are also very easily transportable), making it easier for thieves to steal, transport and then sell on.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T144441Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T144153Z">
        <seg>Trong gần hơn 50 năm qua, đã có sự gia tăng ồ ạt về số lượng đất sở hữu, tài sản và những của cải của người dân (và rất nhiều của cải như đầu DVD, máy tính xách tay, điện thoại di động và TV đều rất dễ để di chuyển), tạo điều kiện cho những kẻ trộm thực hiện hành vi trộm cắp và sau đó mang đi bán. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Perceiving physical health as poor.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172458Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172458Z">
        <seg>Thể trạng kém.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Perhaps the ever-increasing demands for more police on the street is a reflection of the positive relationship the public have with the police.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T164831Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T164122Z">
        <seg>Có lẽ sự gia tăng không ngừng của những nhu cầu cho việc có thêm cảnh sát trên đường phố là một sự phản ánh về mối quan hệ tích cực giữa công chúng và lực lượng cảnh sát.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Peter Tiersma’s (1999) book on legal language traces the history of the adversarial legal system from its origins in William the Conqueror’s invasion of England in 1066.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T132442Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T132442Z">
        <seg>Cuốn sách của Peter Tiersma (1999)về ngôn ngữ pháp lý theo lịch sử của hệ thống pháp luật đối địch từ nguồn gốc của nó trong sách của William cuộc xâm lược của Conqueror ở Anh năm 1066.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Physical injury is also likely with the more direct and physical forms of aggression.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T171823Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T171823Z">
        <seg>Những tổn thương về mặt thể chất là hình thức trực tiếp của các cuộc xung hấn .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Police are more likely than most other professions to be con- fronted with shocking or unexpected events.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T152034Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T151946Z">
        <seg>Cảnh sát, so với các nghề khác, là nghề phải đối mặt với nhiều tình huống khích động và bất ngờ hơn cả.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Police forces in many countries enjoy a positive relationship with the public.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T154052Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T154052Z">
        <seg>Các lực lượng cảnh sát ở nhiều quốc gia thường thích tạo một mối quan hệ tích cực với công chúng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Poor access to prison facilities (e.g. education).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172359Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172359Z">
        <seg>Khó khăn trong việc tiếp cận với các cơ sở vật chất ở nhà tù( ví dụ: Giáo dục).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Poor access to support services.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172434Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172434Z">
        <seg>Thiếu thốn các dịch vụ hỗ trợ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Presumably the more fearful people are the more security they will need.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T144948Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T144948Z">
        <seg>Có thể thất rằng, con người càng có nhiều sợ hãi, họ càng cần nhiều sự bảo vệ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>ProZ.com Forums</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hanthuy" changedate="20130115T181727Z">
        <seg>Diễn đàn ProZ.com</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Programmes are deemed appropriate if they adhere to three principles mentioned above.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T102900Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T102900Z">
        <seg>Những chương trình này sẽ thích hợp hơn nếu họ tuân theo ba nguyên tắc được đề cập ở trên.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Proof beyond a reasonable doubt is proof that leaves you with an abiding conviction that the charge is true.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131141Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131141Z">
        <seg>Bằng chứng dựa trên sự nghi ngờ hợp lý là bằng chứng để lại cho bạn niềm tin mạnh mẽ rằng bản án xử đúng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Psychologists and other social scientists have been researching the effects of imprisonment for some time.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152530Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152530Z">
        <seg>Các nhà tâm lý học và một số nhà khoa học xã hội khác đang nghiêm cứu về tác động khi bị bỏ tù.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Punishment involves some form of pain, discomfort, or generally unpleasant experience.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151006T162007Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151006T161901Z">
        <seg>Sự trừng phạt bao gồm một số đau đớn, bất tiện hoặc nhìn chung là những trải nghiệm khó chịu </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Reasonable doubt is defined as follows: It is not a mere possible doubt; because everything relating to human affairs is open to some possible or imaginary doubt.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T074353Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T074353Z">
        <seg>Nghi ngờ hợp lý được xác định như sau: Nó không phải là một nghi ngờ chỉ có thể; bởi vì tất cả mọi thứ liên quan đến vấn đề con người là mở cửa cho một số nghi ngờ có thể có hoặc tưởng tượng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Recent disasters such as bombings and train crashes, have drawn attention and raised awareness of the fact that the police and other emergency services experience such devastating incidents.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T152455Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T152258Z">
        <seg>Những thảm họa gần đây như đánh bom hay những vụ đâm tàu, đã gây chú ý và cảnh báo rằng cảnh sát cùng những cơ quan khẩn cấp khác đang trải qua những tình huống gây chấn thương như vậy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Reformed instruction (CALCRIM 220).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T130610Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T130610Z">
        <seg>Cải cách hướng dẫn (CALCRIM 220).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Research carried out on adult sexual offenders has shown that the majority say that they started to sexually offend before the age of eighteen, and studies of adolescent sexual offenders indicate that the majority commit their first sexual offence before fifteen years of age and not infrequently before twelve years of age.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T135424Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T135424Z">
        <seg>Nghiên cứu thực hiện trên những tội phạm tình dục trưởng thành đã cho thấy rằng phần lớn họ nghĩ họ bắt đầu lạm dụng tình dục trước 18 tuổi, và những nghiên cứu về những tội phạm tình dục thanh niên cho thấy rằng đa phần thực hiện hành vi xâm phạm trước năm 15 tuổi và không ít người trước 12 tuổi .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Researchers have suggested that there are two types of sexual offence, the sexually aggressive act – which is a non-consensual act – and a breach of a sexual taboo.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153540Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153540Z">
        <seg>Các nhà nghiên cứu cho rằng có hai loại xâm phạm tình dục, hành vi tình dục hung hãn - hành vi tình dục không được đồng thuật - và vi phạm vào hình thức tình dục cấm kỵ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Retribution can take many forms – paying a victim’s family or being shamed for the things that you have done.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T154046Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T154046Z">
        <seg>Sự trừng phạt này có thể có nhiều hình thức - chi trả cho gia đình nạn nhân hoặc bị làm cho nhục nhã vì những gì đã làm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Retribution is not concerned with whether an offender will change in the future; it is about what someone has done.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T134755Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T134755Z">
        <seg>Việc trả thù không quan tâm đến liệu người phạm tội có thay đổi trong tương lai hay không mà nó là về những gì người đó đã làm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Retributive punishments do enable sentencers to come up with a tariff of &lt;t0/&gt;punishments which should be implemented equally.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T132304Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T132304Z">
        <seg>Sự trừng phạt mang tính báo thù này giúp cho những người tuyên án có thể đưa ra bảng giá các hình phạt cái mà cần được thi hành một cách công bằng .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Security has also been developed in terms of manned guards.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T145228Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T145228Z">
        <seg>An ninh cũng được phát triển về những đội bảo vệ có người dẫn dắt.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Sentencers did not start to think about punishment as a deterrent for offenders until the mid-1800s.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T135017Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T135017Z">
        <seg>Những người tuyên án chỉ bắt đầu nghĩ đến sự trừng phạt như 1 biện pháp ngăn chặn kẻ phạm tội cho đến tận giữa những năm 1800 .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Sex offending in the UK includes crimes such as rape (penetration by the penis of someone’s vagina, anus or mouth without consent); assault by penetration (penetration by a body part or object of someone’s vagina or anus without consent); sexual assault (sexual touching); administering a substance with intent to commit a non-consensual sexual act (this covers spiking some- one’s drink); sexual activity with a child (under the age of sixteen), causing or inciting a child to engage in sexual activity; engaging in sexual activity in the presence of a child; meeting a child following sexual grooming (this new offence has been triggered by child abusers using the Internet to meet children); abusing positions of trust (it is unlawful for people who work with children, say in youth services, care homes or schools, to have sex with anyone in their care who is under the age of eighteen).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T160420Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T133550Z">
        <seg>Quấy rối tình dục ở Vương quốc Anh bao gồm những tội như cưỡng hiếp (dùng dương vật xâm nhập vào âm đạo, hậu môn hoặc miệng của một người khác mà không có sự đồng thuận); cưỡng dâm bằng cách xâm nhập (xâm nhập với phần thân của một vật thể vào âm đạo hoặc hậu môn của một người mà không có sự đồng thuận);  tấn công tình dục (đụng chạm thể xác); sử dụng một loại chất với ý đồ thực hiện hành vi tình dục không được đồng thuận (bao gồm cả cho thuốc vào thức uống người khác); hoạt động tình dục với trẻ em (dưới 16 tuổi), sai khiến hoặc xúi giục một đứa trẻ tham gia vào hoạt động tình dục; tham gia vào hoạt động tình dục với sự góp mặt của một đứa trẻ; gặp một đứa trẻ đi bằng cách thiết lập mối quan hệ thân mật với một đứa trẻ nhằm dụ dỗ, lợi dụng nó (phương thức mới được những kẻ lạm dụng tình dục tạo ra bằng việc sử dụng Internet để gặp trẻ em); lạm dụng nhờ tín nhiệm (việc những người làm việc với trẻ em, như trong các dịch vụ thiếu nhi, chăm sóc ở nhà hoặc trường học có quan hệ tình dục với bất cứ ai thuộc phạm vi chăm sóc của họ mà dưới 18 tuổi đều là phạm pháp). </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Sex offending is thought of as a very serious problem within contemporary society.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T131026Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T131026Z">
        <seg>Quấy rối tình dục được biết như là một vấn đề hết sức nghiêm trọng trong xã hội hiện đại.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Shame or guilt and their part in punishment is a key element in Judaism, Christianity and Islam, and there is a clear cross-over within Christian-based cultures between what is ‘sinful’ and what is illegal.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T154359Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T154217Z">
        <seg>Cảm giác nhục nhã hoặc tội lỗi và vai trò của chúng trong việc trừng phạt là yếu tố then chốt trong đạo Do thái, đạo Cơ-đốc và đạo Hồi và có 1 sự giao cắt rõ ràng trong các nên văn hóa có gốc Cơ-đốc giữa cái gì là tội đồ và cài gì là phạm pháp.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Sharing a cell with another prisoner means you have little privacy, as can the physical design of the prison.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T162616Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T162616Z">
        <seg>Việc chia sẻ phòng giam với một tù nhân khác đồng nghĩa bạn sẽ mất bớt sự riêng tư......</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>She examines battles between the accused and the prosecuting lawyer as revealed in their grammatical usage.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T014259Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T014226Z">
        <seg>Cô xem xét cuộc chiến giữa bị cáo và luật sư khởi tố vì những tiết lộ trong cách họ sử dụng ngữ pháp.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Should offenders be given the opportunity of rehabilitation?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Nga" changedate="20151011T045725Z" creationid="Nga" creationdate="20151011T045725Z">
        <seg>Phạm nhân có nên có cơ hội được cải tạo?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Similarly, someone who has a long history of offending or has been convicted of a serious offence (such as a violent or sexual offence) may have different treatment needs from someone who has been caught committing an offence for the very first time.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T120413Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T050342Z">
        <seg>Tương tự, một người có tiền án hoặc đã bị kết án vì một tội ác nghiêm trọng (như tội ác liên quan đến bạo lực hoặc tình dục) có thể sẽ được hưởng chế độ điều trị khác với người mà bị bắt vì phạm tội lần đầu. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Since these criminogenic needs are dynamic or theoretically changeable, treatment that focuses on the resolution of these problems is more likely to be associated with a reduction in recidivism.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T033644Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T033040Z">
        <seg>Từ khi Các nhu cầu dẫn đến phạm tội thay đổi về lý thuyết đã tạo động lực cho việc điều trị - chúng dần tập trung vào việc kiên quyết làm sáng tỏ các vấn đề có thể gắn liền với giảm bớt xu hướng tái phạm tội. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Smoking can be conceptualized as problem behaviour in much the same way as criminal behaviour can.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T034916Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T034355Z">
        <seg>Có thể nhận thấy rằng, hút thuốc lá được ví như vấn đề về cách cư xử và nó cũng khá giống với hành vi phạm tội.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>So, a mugger is not likely to be executed, and a murderer is not likely be sentenced to a community penalty.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T131138Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T131138Z">
        <seg>Vì thế nên 1 tên trộm cướp thì không thể bị xử tử và 1 tên sát nhân thì không thể chỉ bị phạt lao động công ích.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>So, if someone killed a man, the murderer had to pay 100 shillings to the victim’s family.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T151929Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T151929Z">
        <seg>Vì thế nếu giết 1 người đàn ông, tên sát nhân phải trả 100 shillings cho gia đình nạn nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>So, when considering the numbers of people affected by imprisonment, how many are we actually talking about?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T151934Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T151934Z">
        <seg>Vậy thì, khi xem xét số lượng người bị tác động bởi việc bỏ tù, thực sự chúng ta đang đề cập đến bao nhiêu người?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Social loneliness may result from rumour-spreading or ostracism if the peer group withdraws from the victim.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T172153Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T172153Z">
        <seg>Cảm giác cô đơn, lạc lõng trong tập thể có thể là kết quả từ sự lan truyền các lời đồn đại hoặc bị tẩy chay nếu  những thành viên trong nhóm dừng giao tiếp với nạn nhân .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Solan and other researchers show how these different constructions affect the jury’s decision- making and can lead either to higher or lower conviction rates.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T073440Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T073440Z">
        <seg>Solan và các nhà nghiên cứu khác cho thấy làm thế nào các cách đặt câu khác nhau ảnh hưởng đến việc ra quyết định của ban giám khảo và có thể dẫn đến hoặc là tỷ lệ kết án cao hơn hoặc thấp hơn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Some have focused on the criminal setting and have been based on experienced investigators’ beliefs about such cues.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T095424Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T095424Z">
        <seg>Một số tập trung vào hệ thống sắp đặt tội phạm và dựa vào niềm tin của những điều tra viên kinh nghiệm về những dấu hiệu ấy </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Some newspaper reports would suggest not.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152238Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152238Z">
        <seg>Một vài báo cáo trên các tờ báo cho rằng không nên.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Some of the factors that have been reported to be associated with suicide in prison include:</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T174154Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T174154Z">
        <seg>Một vài yếu tố đã được cho là có liên quan đến việc gây tự tử trong tù bao gồm:</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Some researchers have tried to counter these problems by utilizing self-report information from the individuals themselves or asking their family, friends and other associates about the individuals’ behaviour.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T120202Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T161421Z">
        <seg>Một vài nhà nghiên cứu đã cố gắng phản đối vấn đề này bằng cách tận dụng thông tin tự thuật từ nhiều cá nhân hoặc hỏi gia đình, bạn bè, người quen của họ về cách họ cư xử thường ngày.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Some theorists have expressed their concerns that if the discomfort of imprisonment is too great, it can be counterproductive.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T161554Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T161554Z">
        <seg>Một số nhà tư tưởng đã bày tỏ quan ngại những bất tiện khi ở tù là quá nhiều và nó có thể cản trở những mục tiêu thực sự của việc giam giữ .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Someone who completes a programme may have subsequently committed a dozen or more crimes but as he or she was not caught and reconvicted, it would appear that the programme was effective.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151008T160613Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T160613Z">
        <seg>Một người nào đó đã phạm một tá tội lỗi hoặc nhiều hơn nhưng vì anh hoặc cô ta không bị bắt và bị tái kết án, nên chương trình điều trị sẽ có hiệu quả hơn. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Specifically, they are focusing on the goals of punishment and deterrence.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T160451Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T160451Z">
        <seg>Nói một cách cụ thể hơn, nhà tù được lập ra với mục đích để trừng phạt kẻ ác và ngăn chặn việc xấu.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Studies on this topic compare the childhood and development of sex offenders with non-sexual offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153730Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153730Z">
        <seg>Những nghiên cứu về chủ đề này so sánh tuổi thơ và sự phát triển của tội phạm tình dục với những tội phạm khác.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Studies with smaller samples of participants are therefore less likely to detect any effect of treatment (if indeed one exists).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151008T052006Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T050456Z">
        <seg>Nghiên cứu với số lượng người tham gia mẫu nhỏ hơn ít có thể tìm ra bất cứ ảnh hưởng nào của việc điều trị (nếu mà nó thật sự có tồn tại). </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Such research can aim to increase our understanding of what imprisonment is like with a view to enhancing rehabilitative efforts or it may focus on the evaluation of the effectiveness of psychological interventions in place.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T151832Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T151822Z">
        <seg>Các nghiên cứu này hoặc hướng tới nâng cao sự hiểu biết cho mọi người về việc giam giữ để có thể thúc đẩy những nỗ lực tái hòa nhập hoặc tập trung vào việc đánh giá tính hiệu quả của việc can thiệp tâm lý ở trong tù.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Taken from the website www.languageandlaw.org</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131343Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131343Z">
        <seg>Được lấy từ website www.languageandlaw.org</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>That is, although relevant professionals and lay people in several countries share the same beliefs about supposed cues to lying, these beliefs are largely wrong.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T095501Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T095501Z">
        <seg>
Tức là , mặc dù những chuyên gia trong ngành và những người không có chuyên môn ở nhiều quốc gia có chung niềm tin về những dấu hiệu được cho là của nói dối, những niềm tin đó hầu hết là không đúng</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The British police are proud to remain routinely unarmed, retain the principal of minimum force and carry a minimal amount of equipment for their own protection.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T163314Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T162625Z">
        <seg>Cảnh sát Anh quốc luôn tự hào về việc thường xuyên giữ trạng thái không trang bị vũ trang, duy trì lực lượng chủ yếu ở mức thấp nhất và mang theo cực ít các thiết bị bảo vệ bản thân .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The Federal version of Megan’s Law, which was passed in May 1996, signed by President Clinton, is different.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T162353Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T162353Z">
        <seg>Phiên bản liên bang của Luật Megan được thông qua vào 5/1996, kí bởi tổng thống Clinton, thì khác.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children (NSPCC) reports that one in six children are sexually abused before the age of sixteen and that children are far more likely to be abused by someone they know (a family member or a &lt;t0/&gt;neighbour&lt;t1/&gt;) than by a stranger.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T133922Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T133801Z">
        <seg>Hiệp hội Phòng chống ngược đã trẻ em của Anh (NSPCC) thống kê rằng cứ 6 trẻ em thì có 1 em bị lạm dụng tình dục trước tuổi 16 và các em ấy thường bị lạm dụng bởi những người quen (thành viên trong gia đình hoặc hàng xóm) nhiều hơn là bởi một người lạ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The UK Home Office has recently proposed that research adopting arandomized control trial design (RCT: offenders are randomly assigned to either the intervention or a no-intervention group and their outcomes compared) is the highest standard possible.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151007T170450Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T165221Z">
        <seg>Bộ nội vụ vương quốc Anh gần đây đã đề xuất một giải pháp là nghiên cứu thiết kế những phiên tòa có sự điều khiển thông qua việc sắp xếp ngẫu nhiên (RCT: phạm nhân được chỉ định ngẫu nhiên với một nhóm có sự can thiệp hoặc không rồi sánh kết quả) là tiêu chuẩn cao nhất có thể thực hiện được .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The above factors have been conceptualized into the three principles of risk, need and responsivity of offender rehabilitation.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T121022Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T101919Z">
        <seg>Tóm lại, những yếu tố trên được quan niệm như là ba nguyên tắc: nguyên tắc nguy cơ, nguyên tắc nhu cầu và nguyên tắc đáp ứng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The author of a study with a small sample size that yields no detectable treatment effect may conclude that the treatment is ineffective and should therefore be dis- continued.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151012T162239Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T051227Z">
        <seg>Tác giả của một công trình nghiên cứu trên kích thước mẫu nhỏ không thể phát hiện ra kết quả điều trị đã kết luận rằng phương pháp điều trị này thiếu hiệu quả và nên sớm kết thúc.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The box above summarizes the evidence-based criteria that the CSAP have adopted.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151007T145437Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T145437Z">
        <seg>Bảng tóm tắt bên trên căn cứ theo tiêu chí mà CSAP đã thông qua.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The call to discontinue the treatment programme based on such small studies could therefore be premature.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T115656Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T052324Z">
        <seg>Vì thế, những chương trình điều trị dựa trên một số nghiên cứu nhỏ nên ngừng thực hiện sớm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The chapter will also talk about the effectiveness of these treatments; do the punishments work?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T130811Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T130811Z">
        <seg>Chương này cũng sẽ nói về hiệu quả của những phương pháp điều trị này; những hình phạt có tác dụng hay không?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The choice of which indicator of treatment success (or failure) to use is also an important consideration in this type of research (which is often called treatment–outcome research).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T115825Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T053429Z">
        <seg>Bên cạnh đó, việc lựa chọn yếu tố nào quyết định thành công (hoặc thất bại) của chương trình điều trị cũng cần được xem xét kỷ lưỡng trong nghiên cứu dạng này (nó thường được gọi là nghiên cứu điều trị-kết quả).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The counter argument to this is that the specialized words and use of words allows for the precision that is necessary in the legal context.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T144808Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T144808Z">
        <seg>Các lập luận phản biện này là những từ chuyên ngành và sử dụng từ ngữ cho phép độ chính xác đó là cần thiết trong bối cảnh pháp lý.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The crime of rape is clearly a very serious one and whether someone is convicted can depend upon the question of consent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T011143Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T011143Z">
        <seg>Tội hiếp dâm rõ ràng là rất nghiêm trọng và liệu có ai đó bị kết án có thể phụ thuộc vào các câu hỏi về sự đồng thuận.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The current reality is very far removed from this.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T071809Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T071809Z">
        <seg>Thực tế hiện nay khác xa quan điểm này.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The defendant’s response is to diffuse this and represent the actions back to the lawyer as joint actions; ‘we started kissing’, ‘we started to fool around again’ or actions of indeterminate nature ‘all our clothes at one point were taken off and we were fooling around’.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T015510Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T015510Z">
        <seg>Bị cáo trả lời để đưa thông tin và miêu tả những hành động cho luật sư như là những hoạt động chung; ' chúng tôi bắt đầu hôn, 'chúng tôi quên hết xung quanh một lần nữa' hoặc những hành động không xác định 'tất cả quần áo ở chỗ được cởi ra và chúng tôi quấn lấy nhau'.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The development of these ‘What Works’ principles has inevitably been reliant on the conclusions of research studies.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T153029Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T150032Z">
        <seg>Sự phát triển của những nguyên tắc 'Hoạt động thế nào' chắc hẳn đã dựa vào những kết luận của các công trình nghiên cứu.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The evidence need not eliminate all possible doubt because everything in life is open to some possible or imaginary doubt.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131326Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131326Z">
        <seg>Những bằng chứng cần thiết không loại trừ tất cả khả năng có thể bởi vì mọi thứ trong cuộc sống mở ra vài nghi ngờ có thể và tưởng tượng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The exception was that week at Hatfield, when there was a great deal more action and violence than normal.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T145528Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T145528Z">
        <seg>Tuần ấy ở Hatfield là một trường hợp ngoại lệ, khi đó đã có xô xát và bạo lực nhiều hơn bình thường.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The first draws on the history of our legal systems; the second is more functional in trying to understand the purpose of legal language.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T132037Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T132037Z">
        <seg>Việc đầu tiên dựa trên lịch sử của hệ thống pháp luật; thứ hai là chức năngthêm vào trong việc cố gắng để hiểu được mục đích của ngôn ngữ pháp lý.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The following section will explore these principles in more depth and will assess how they are important when matching an offender to the right intervention.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T103238Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T103238Z">
        <seg>Phần tiếp theo sẽ khảo sát những nguyên tắc này kỹ lưỡng hơn và sẽ đánh giá chúng quan trọng thế nào khi áp dụng với người phạm tội bằng các biện pháp can thiệp đúng đắn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The human and financial cost of sexual offending to victims and the social and health services is large, as is the public investment in policing, prosecuting and incarcerating sex offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T160441Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T160703Z">
        <seg>Chi phí nhân lực và tài chính dành cho những nạn nhân của lạm dụng tình dục và các dịch vụ xã hội cũng như sức khoẻ khá lớn, cũng như là đầu tư của cộng đồng về chính sách, khởi tố và tống giam những kẻ quấy rối tình dục.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The main impetus for criminal psychologists to address the issue of witness testimony has come from concerns about false convictions.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T030936Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151012T030923Z">
        <seg>Nỗi lo về việc kết án oan chính là động lực chính thúc đẩy các nhà tâm lý học tội phạm tìm cách giải quyết vấn đề chứng thực lời khai của nhân chứng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The model, he suggests, should be one of a teacher explaining something complex to a class.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T071722Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T071722Z">
        <seg>Ông ấy gợi ý mô hình này nên được giảng những thứ phức tạp trong lớp học.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The nature of punishment for wrongdoing, just as the nature of crime, changes over time and across cultures.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T150846Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T150846Z">
        <seg>Bản chất của việc trừng phạt những hành động phạm pháp, giống như bản chất của tội ác, thay đổi theo thời gian và theo các văn hóa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The number of participants utilized in the research is import- ant, as the statistics employed to measure any effect brought about by participation in the programme are sensitive to the size of the sample under investigation.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T153221Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T172228Z">
        <seg>Ngoài ra, số lượng người tham gia nghiên cứu cũng rất quan trọng, vì thống kê sử dụng để đo lường bất cứ tác động nào gây ra bởi người tham gia chương trình. Họ là những người rất nhạy cảm với kích cỡ của mẫu vật thu được khi điều tra.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The precision required in legal language requires it to be as context independent as possible.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T145456Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T145456Z">
        <seg>Sự chính xác được trong ngôn ngữ pháp lý đòi hỏi nó phải được đặt trong hoàn cảnh độc lập tối đa có thể.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The prison environment is stressful by its very nature and several researchers have examined the stressors operating in prisons.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T161858Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T161858Z">
        <seg>Bản thân môi trường ở nhà tù đã rất căng thẳng và rất nhiều nhà nghiên cứu đã tiến hành kiểm tra các nhân tố gây căng thẳng đó </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The public shaming of offenders played a big part of punishments until the middle of the sixteenth century, but public hangings carried on for a long time after this in the UK and parts of Europe (think about the guillotining of the aristocracy in Revolutionary France), which might also be seen as shameful for the offenders and their families.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T153549Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T153549Z">
        <seg>Việc bêu riếu công khai những kẻ phạm tội có vai trò lớn trong việc trừng phạt cho đến giữa thế kỷ thứ 16, nhưng việc treo cổ công khai vẫn được tiến hành sau đó ở Anh và 1 số phần ở châu Âu (hãy nghĩ đến việc chém đầu các quý tộc trong cuộc cách mạng Pháp) cái mà cũng có thể được coi là nhục nhã với kẻ phạm tội và gia đình của chúng .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The question as to why these historical structures and phrases remain in the language can be debated.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T144649Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T144649Z">
        <seg>Câu hỏi là tại sao những cấu trúc lịch sử và cụm từ vẫn còn trong ngôn ngữ có thể được thảo luận.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The question of whether offenders who behave in a similar manner during their crimes also share similar demographic characteristics has been examined using a sample of stranger rapists, but the study found no evidence to support this.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="The sun" changedate="20151007T024351Z" creationid="The sun" creationdate="20151007T024351Z">
        <seg>Nghi vấn rằng liệu những kẻ phạm tội cư xử giống nhau trong khi phạm tội cũng có chung những đặc điểm nhân khẩu học đã được kiểm chứng qua việc sử dụng một hình mẫu những kẻ hiếp dâm lạ mặt, tuy nhiên nghiên cứu không đưa ra được bằng chứng để chứng minh điều đó.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The range of punishments available, and acceptable, are a mixture of the retributive and reductivist.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151010T030735Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151010T030735Z">
        <seg>Mức trừng phạt đang tồn tại và được chấp nhận là sự kết hợp giữa tính báo thù và tính thu hẹp  .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The reform of legal language is not restricted to courtroom situations.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131457Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131457Z">
        <seg>Sự cải cách ngôn ngữ pháp lý không giới hạn ở trong phòng xử án.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The reformed instruction on reasonable doubt is given above.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T073928Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T073928Z">
        <seg>Các hướng dẫn cải cách trên sự nghi ngờ hợp lý được đưa ra ở trên.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The research that has been conducted has found that imprisonment can have very negative effects for some prisoners.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T155156Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T155104Z">
        <seg>Nghiên cứu đã được thực hiện chỉ ra rằng việc bắt giam có tác động rất tiêu cực tới một số tù nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The risk principle states that those offenders who are more likely to reoffend, or, in other words, are at a higher risk of reoffending, should receive a greater level or intensity of intervention than those who are at a lower risk of reoffending.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151012T164252Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T104051Z">
        <seg>Nguyên tắc nguy cơ phát biểu rằng những người phạm tội thường có nhiều khả năng tái phạm, nghĩa là, họ có nguy cơ tái phạm cao hoặc cường độ can thiệp của họ cao hơn những người có nguy cơ tái phạm thấp. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The term ‘offender profiling’ is one with which most of us are familiar.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T035554Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T024449Z">
        <seg>Thuật ngữ "thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm" là một thuật ngữ mà hầu hết chúng ta đều quen thuộc.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The thinking behind this is that those who are lower risk are less likely to reoffend and hence are less likely to need an intervention to help them desist from crime.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T104559Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T104401Z">
        <seg>Một ý kiến khác cho rằng những người ở nguy cơ tái phạm thấp hơn thì ít có khả năng tái phạm và vì thế cũng ít cần can thiệp để giúp họ ngừng phạm tội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The understanding of language is rarely dependent on the words alone.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T145549Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T145549Z">
        <seg>Sự hiểu biết về ngôn ngữ là hiếm khi phụ thuộc vào từ ngữ mà thôi.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The use of the psychologist as an expert witness has, in the past, been constricted by the notion of the expert having to provide information that is beyond the knowledge of the average person.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151007T091253Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151007T091253Z">
        <seg>Trong quá khứ thì việc sử dụng các nhà tâm lý học bị thắt chặt bởi định nghĩa về việc các nhân chứng chuyên gia cung cấp thông tin ngoài tâm hiểu biết thông thường của mọi người. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The victims might have withheld it, or they might not have been in a position to give consent to the sexual act (for example, they might be under the age of consent, be mentally disabled, drunk, drugged or unconscious).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153443Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153443Z">
        <seg>Nạn nhân đã có thể từ chối nó, hoặc họ có thể ở một tình thế nào đó cho phép hành động xâm hại ( như là họ dưới độ tuổi đồng thuận, bị bệnh tâm thần, bị chuốc say, bị đánh thuốc hoặc vô thức).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>The way that expert witnesses are called to the court, however, varies from one jurisdiction to another.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151007T082749Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151007T082749Z">
        <seg>Cách mà các nhân chứng chuyên gia được triệu tập và thẩm quyền của họ có thể khác nhau tùy theo từng khu vực .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Their behaviour may well be more engrained than that of the first time offender and hence a greater depth of behaviour modification is needed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T120838Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T051909Z">
        <seg>Hành vi của họ có thể ăn sâu vào tiềm thức hơn so với lần đầu phạm tội và vì thế thực sự cần sự thay đổi toàn diện trong cách cư xử cũng như hành vi của họ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>There are a number of different ways in which sexual offending has been explained.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153651Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153651Z">
        <seg>Có nhiều các để giải thích về xâm phạm tình dục.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>There are some examples, when a jury has asked &lt;t0/&gt;for further explanation of an issue, where the judge has simply re-read the instruction to the jury.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T071945Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T071945Z">
        <seg>Có một số ví dụ, khi một bồi thẩm đoàn yêu cầu để giải thích thêm về một vấn đề, nơi mà các thẩm phán đã chỉ đơn giản là đọc lại các hướng dẫn cho bồi thẩm đoàn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>There has been some concern about the increasing role these security agencies play in relation to the public, especially as until recently there was no legislation in England and Wales in place to regulate or control the private security industry.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T151014Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T150941Z">
        <seg>Đã có những lo ngại về sự gia tăng trong vai trò của các văn phòng cơ sở an ninh trong cộng đồng, đặc biệt là cho đến gần đây, vẫn chưa có luật pháp nào của Anh và xứ Wales được đặt ra để điều tiết hoặc quản lý ngành an ninh tư nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>There is no single cause of sexual offending and our understanding of what makes someone a sexual offender is far from perfect.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153634Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153634Z">
        <seg>Không chỉ có một lí do tạo ra xâm phạm tình dục mà hiểu biết của chúng ta về cái làm nên một tội phạm tình dục vẫn còn rất hạn hẹp.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>There were reports of poisoners being boiled in cauldrons, thieves being whipped, rapists being branded, prostitutes being tied to posts with notes declaring their offences pinned to their dresses, debtors being tied backwards to horses and taken around a town, and bigamists being drawn (dragged from place to place on a piece of wood behind a horse) and then burned.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T153106Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T153106Z">
        <seg>Đã có nhiều báo cáo về những tên đầu độc bị đun trong vạc, trôm cắp bị vụt, tên hiếp dâm bị đóng dấu bằng sắt nung, gái mại dâm bị trói vào cột và bị dán những ghi chép buộc tội sự xúc phạm của họ lên quần áo, những con nợ bị trói ngược vào ngựa và lôi đi khắp phố và những người vi phạm qui tắc 1 vợ 1 chống bị kéo ( lôi từ chỗ này sang chỗ khác trên 1 miếng gỗ sau 1 con ngựa) rồi bị thiêu sống .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>These include:</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153700Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153700Z">
        <seg>Bao gồm:</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>These instructions were the result of a committee to which Tiersma contributed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T073903Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T073903Z">
        <seg>Những hướng dẫn này là kết quả của một hội đồng với đóng góp của Tiersma.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>These may range from requiring materials to be provided in their first language, to the programme needing to address cultural or religious issues which may impact on the process of treatment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T093037Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T093037Z">
        <seg>Vùng dữ liệu cần thiết cần được cung cấp từ ngôn ngữ đầu tiên của họ, để nhận định những ảnh hưởng trong quá trình điều trị từ nhiều vấn đề liên quan đến văn hóa và tôn giáo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>These needs can be classified into two different types: criminogenic and non-criminogenic.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T032213Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T031934Z">
        <seg>Những nhu cầu này được phân loại thành hai dạng khác nhau: gây ra tội ác hoặc không.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>These negative effects of being victimized in prison can be compounded by the inmate code, which discourages informing on fellow prisoners: it can be particularly difficult for prisoners to seek help from staff.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T172630Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T172630Z">
        <seg>Những hiệu ứng tiêu cực của việc bị ngược đãi trong tù có thể trở nên tồi tệ hơn bằng việc dùng những mật mã/quy ước của các bạn tù, đây là điều gây trở ngại cho sự tổ cáo những người chung tù. Điều này có thể trở nên cực kì phức tạp cho tù nhân trong việc tìm kiếm sự giúp đỡ từ các nhân viên trong tù.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>These one-off traumatic events may have a profound and devastating effect.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T152139Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T152027Z">
        <seg>Những sự kiện gây thương chấn này có thể để lại những tàn phá và ảnh hưởng sâu sắc.These one-off traumatic events may have a profound and devastating effect.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>These reforms saw the introduction of English as the language of statutes and parliamentary debates.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T144038Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T144038Z">
        <seg>Những cải cách này làm cho tiếng Anh trở thành ngôn ngữ của đạo luật và các cuộc tranh luận của quốc hội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>They have performed analyses of courtroom questioning by lawyers, of witness language and of judges’ language in their rulings and in their instructions to juries.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T010051Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T010051Z">
        <seg>Họ đã thực hiện các phân tích câu hỏi trong phòng xử án của luật sư, lời khai của nhân chứng, các phát quyết của thẩm phán và trong các hướng dẫn của họ đến bồi thẩm đoàn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>They try to find out what the differences are in the histories of these people, which will then, hopefully, show whether there is a childhood trigger for sexual offending.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153741Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153741Z">
        <seg>Họ cố tìm ra sự khác biệt trong quá khứ của những người này, và hi vọng sẽ biết được thời thơ ấu có gây ra hành vi xâm phạm tình dục hay không.
</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Think about whether a woman who has been subjected to twenty years of domestic abuse and kills her husband during an incident is to ‘blame’ in the same way as a woman who kills her husband because she wishes to leave him and be with her lover.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T132903Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T132903Z">
        <seg>Hãy tưởng tượng nếu 1 người phụ nữ phải chịu đựng sự bao lực gia đình trong 20 năm và vô tình giết chồng cô ta trong 1 tai nạn thì cũng phải chịu tội giống như 1 người phụ nữ khác giết chồng mình vì cô ta muốn bỏ anh ta để đi theo người tình.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This can result from the actual experience of being imprisoned or it can be related to a person’s encounters with others whilst imprisoned.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T155549Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T155147Z">
        <seg>Điều này có thể xuất phát từ những trải nghiệm thực tế khi bị giam giữ hoặc liên quan tới việc va chạm giữa một người với những người khác trong quá trình ở tù.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This chapter will look at how criminal psychology helps us understand some of the reasons why men and women become sex offenders and how sex offenders are punished, treated and managed once they are caught.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T130721Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T130721Z">
        <seg>Chương này sẽ nói đến cách tâm lý học tội phạm giúp chúng ta hiểu một số lí do tại sao đàn ông và đàn bà trở thành những tội phạm tình dục và những kẻ tội phạm tình dục bị xử phạt, đối xử và quản lí như thế nào khi họ bị bắt. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This concept of ‘reason- able doubt’ has been explained to juries in different ways across different jurisdictions.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T073043Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T073043Z">
        <seg>Khái niệm về 'nghi ngờ ở mức hợp lý "đã được giải thích cho bồi thẩm đoàn trong nhiều cách khác nhau trên khắp khu vực pháp lý khác nhau.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This construction of consent as being presumed, unless clearly withdrawn, links with &lt;t0/&gt;Erhlich’s&lt;t1/&gt; ideological discussion of USA rape law.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T032912Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T025419Z">
        <seg>Người ta coi như là có sự đồng thuận, trừ khi có sự từ chối rõ ràng, liên kết với các cuộc thảo luận quan điểm của Erhlich của luật hiếp dâm Mỹ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This form of reasoning, known as Utilitarianism, was developed by the English philosopher Jeremy Bentham during the early 1800s.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T140843Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T140843Z">
        <seg>Dạng lập luận này hay được biết đến là thuyết vị lợi được phát triển bởi 1 nhà triết học người Anh Jeremy Bentham trong đầu những năm 1800.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This has resulted in a greater demand for a uniformed presence on the streets which has been recognized by recent Government policy documents.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T142906Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T142906Z">
        <seg>Việc này đã dẫn đến những yêu cầu lớn hơn về sự có mặt của những cảnh sát mặc quân phục, điều đã được công nhận trong các văn bản chính sách của chính phủ gần đây.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This has resulted in uniformed private security guards interacting with the public on a day to day basis.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T145956Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T145900Z">
        <seg>Điều này dẫn đến kết quả những đội bảo vệ mặc đồng phục tư nhân tương tác với công chúng hầu như mỗi ngày.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This high proportion may be an indication that people still find it difficult to believe that women can be sex offenders too.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T155132Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T155132Z">
        <seg>Con số cao này có lẽ biểu thị rằng người dân vẫn cảm thấy khó tin với việc phụ nữ cũng có thể là tội phạm tình dục.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This involves reducing the likelihood of false identifications while enabling correct identifications to occur.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151007T015507Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151007T014058Z">
        <seg>Để làm được điều này, cần giảm thiểu khả năng xuất hiện lỗi đồng thời cho phép những lần nhận diện chính xác xảy ra.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This is based on getting offenders to consider their past behaviour and think about changing their future behaviour – going from being criminals to law-abiding citizens.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T141603Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151008T141603Z">
        <seg>Điều này dựa trên việc khiến cho những kẻ phạm tội cân nhắc những hành vi của mình trong quá khứ và nghĩ đến việc thay đổi lối cư xử trong tương lai - từ những kẻ tội phạm thành những công dân tuân thù pháp luật.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This is the notion of ‘just deserts’, that offenders are subject to a punishment that is equal to the crime that they have committed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151008T130950Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T160230Z">
        <seg>Đây chính là khái niệm " hình phạt thích đáng" trong đó kẻ phạm tội là mục tiêu của sự trừng phạt tương đương với tội mà họ đã phạm phải.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This law requires States to release information to the public about offenders, but it does not require them to ‘actively notify’ the public.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T162516Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T162516Z">
        <seg>Luật này yêu cầu các Bang phải phát tán thông tin cho cộng đồng về các tội phạm, nhưng nó không yêu cầu họ phải "thiết thực thông báo" đến công chúng. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This means that information about offenders’ names and addresses is made accessible to the public in listings at criminal justice agencies, registry books, or electronic formats (for example, on some police Internet sites).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T162900Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151011T162655Z">
        <seg>Điều này có nghĩa là thông tin về tội phạm như tên và địa chỉ thì công chúng có thể tiếp cận được với những danh sách ở các cơ quan công lý, sổ đăng ký hoặc những mẩu tin điện tử (ví dụ như các trang web cảnh sát). </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This might also be the case if a victim’s property is damaged.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T171653Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T171653Z">
        <seg>Đây cũng có thể là trường hợp mà tài sản cá nhân của một nạn nhân nào đó bị xâm hại.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This practice has been referred to by other names including criminal profiling, psychological profiling and specific profile analysis.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T034835Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T034835Z">
        <seg>Hoạt động này được gọi chung bằng những tên gọi khác nhau bao gồm thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm, thiết lập hồ sơ tâm lý và phân tích hồ sơ cụ thể.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This research found that those who dropped out of treatment at that time were at a higher risk of reconviction than those who went on to complete it.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T111140Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T111140Z">
        <seg>Nghiên cứu này nhận ra rằng những người dừng tham gia điều trị lúc đó sẽ có nguy cơ tái phạm cao hơn những người tiếp tục hoàn thành việc điều trị. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This section explores people’s attitudes towards punishment, what happens when the State does not punish wrongdoers and whether it is right for communities to take the law into their own hands and punish deviants.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151010T031444Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151010T031444Z">
        <seg>Trong phần này chúng ta sẽ khám phá thái đọ của con người về việc trừng phạt, điều gì sẽ xảy ra nếu chính quyề không xử phạt những người phạm pháp và liệu .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This stated that when sex offenders are released into the community, that community will be ‘actively notified’ of their presence.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151011T162006Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T163652Z">
        <seg>Luật này phát biểu rằng khi những tội phạm tình dục được thả tự do về cộng đồng, nơi đó sẽ được "thiết thực thông báo" về sự hiện diện của những người này.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This system comprised a Joint Prison and Probation Accreditation Panel (now entitled the Correctional Services Accreditation Panel – CSAP) which was set up in order to ensure that programmes developed for offenders in prison and on probation were grounded in the best available research evidence of the day.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T114657Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151007T045641Z">
        <seg>Hệ thống này bao gồm Cơ quan quản lý nhà tù và giám sát phạm nhân (bây giờ gọi là Ban cải huấn và chứng nhận gọi tắt là CSAP) được thành lập để đảm bảo chương trình phát triển cho những phạm nhân nhận án tù và án treo, họ sẽ được hỗ trợ những bằng chứng nghiên cứu có sẵn tốt nhất hiện nay. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This type of research, however, can be time-consuming, expensive to conduct and is only ever as good as the accuracy of the reports received.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151008T162251Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T162131Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, nghiên cứu loại này có thể tốn thời gian, chi phí thực hiện khá đắt và kết quả thì chẳng mấy khi đúng như những báo cáo được nhận.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>This was an increase on the previous year by 8,000 crimes, but in this period the Sex Offences Act 2003 came into force meaning that new offences, such as grooming and abuse of trust, were taken into account.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T161009Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T134124Z">
        <seg>Đây là một sự tăng trưởng so với năm ngoái với 8,000 trường hợp, nhưng trong khoảng thời gian này, Đạo luật về Xâm phạm tình dục 2003 đã đi đến quyết định là những phương thức mới, như dụ dỗ và lạm dụng nhờ tín nhiệm đều phải được ghi nhận.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Those offenders who have made crime their way of life may only benefit from a more intense intervention which addresses a range of needs.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T051447Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T050759Z">
        <seg>Với những phạm nhân gây án có thế thể chỉ hưởng lợi từ sự can thiệp cứng rắn để khoanh vùng nhu cầu của họ. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Three months after her murder the State of New Jersey passed the first version of Megan’s Law.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T163629Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T163629Z">
        <seg>Ba tháng sau cái chết của cô bé, bang New Jersey đã thông qua phiên bản đầu tiên của Luật Megan.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Through analysis of language, understanding can be gained of how power works in the courtroom, of how witnesses are likely to respond to certain types of questions and of what is likely to confuse or inform juries.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T010725Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T010725Z">
        <seg>Thông qua phân tích ngôn ngữ, có thể hiểu được sức mạnh các công việc trong phòng xử án, về cách nhân chứng có khả năng đáp ứng với một số loại câu hỏi và những gì có khả năng gây nhầm lẫn hoặc thông báo cho bồi thẩm đoàn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Through bullying others, prisoners can obtain, from other inmates, resources that are of limited availability in prison, such as tobacco and telephone cards.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151012T170901Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151012T170901Z">
        <seg>Bằng các hành hạ, bắt nạt người khác, những tù nhân có thể giành được từ các bạn tù những vật dụng bị hạn chế sử dụng trong thù như thuốc lá và thẻ điện thoại.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Throughout its history the British police has worked on the principle of being unarmed, uniformed citizens.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T163739Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T163739Z">
        <seg>Xuyên suốt lịch sử đất nước, cảnh sát Anh đã luôn làm việc dựa trên nguyên tắc không trang bị vũ trang, như những công dân mặc quân phục.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Thus &lt;t0/&gt;it would seem that not only is it necessary to target those individuals who are most in need of treatment, but it is also necessary to support such individuals through to successful completion of the programme.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T112218Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T111823Z">
        <seg>Thế nên dường như, không những việc định vị các cá nhân cần điều trị là rất cần thiết, mà việc ủng hộ những người đã kết thúc thành công chương trình đó cũng đặc biệt quan trọng. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Thus Ehrlich shows how the lawyer’s questions presuppose the defendant’s responsibility for his actions: ‘you proceeded to touch her’, ‘you laid down beside her’ and ‘you then started kissing her’.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T014712Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T014712Z">
        <seg>Như vậy Ehrlich cho thấy làm thế nào câu hỏi của luật sư giả định trách nhiệm của bị cáo cho hành động của mình: 'bạn tiến hành chạm vào cô ấy', 'bạn nằm xuống bên cạnh cô ấy' và 'sau đó bạn bắt đầu hôn cô ấy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>To demonstrate this point an analogy can be drawn between an offender attempting to abstain from offending and a person who is attempting to abstain from smoking cigarettes.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T034249Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T034249Z">
        <seg>Để minh họa quan điểm này, khi so sánh những điểm giống nhau giữa nỗ lực kiêng hút thuốc lá của một người với nỗ lực tiết chế hành vi phạm tội của một phạm nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Today is Monday.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Dale Nguyen" changedate="20150912T152903Z" creationid="Dale Nguyen" creationdate="20150912T152903Z">
        <seg>Hôm nay là thứ hai.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Together with the perception that the police are being removed from public view, other changes have occurred in society that have resulted in a greater need for security.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151011T143527Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151011T143527Z">
        <seg>Cùng với sự nhận thức về vấn đề cảnh sát đang dần bị tách khỏi công chúng, những thay đổi khác cũng được áp dụng trong công đồng và đã dẫn đến nhu cầu lớn hơn về an ninh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Tomorrow is Tuesday.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Dale Nguyen" changedate="20151006T134600Z" creationid="Dale Nguyen" creationdate="20151006T134600Z">
        <seg>Ngày mai là thứ ba.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Under these circumstances expert witnesses are permitted to provide their opinion (rather than the facts) on the issue being discussed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151007T082007Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151007T082007Z">
        <seg> Trong trường hợp đó, các nhân chứng chuyên gia được phép nêu ra các ý kiến của họ(không những là sự thật mà còn là suy luận) về vấn đề đang được nói đến.Under these circumstances expert witnesses are permitted to provide their opinion (rather than the facts) on the issue being discussed.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Unfortunately, recent criminal psych- ology research has found much of what such books claim to be signs of deceit to be mistaken.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T095441Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T095441Z">
        <seg>Thật không may, những nghiên cứu về tâm lý học tội phạm gần đây đã chỉ ra rằng nhiều trong số những điều được cho là dấu hiệu của sự lừa dối đó đã bị hiểu sai</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Unfortunately, the concern to be legally watertight has led to some instructions being largely incomprehensible to the ordinary men and women of the jury.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T055127Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T055127Z">
        <seg>Không may mắn là quy định pháp lí chặt chẽ của ban bồi thẩm đưa ra những hướng dẫn mà hầu hết người bình thường không hiểu được.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Unfortunately, the media portrayal of offender profiling has often been far from accurate.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T030447Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T025332Z">
        <seg>Tuy nhiên, không may là sự miêu tả của truyền thông về việc thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm thường không chính xác.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Unless we have visited a prison or have been imprisoned ourselves, most of what we know of imprisonment comes from the television or other media.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T152423Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T152423Z">
        <seg>Trừ khi bạn đã từng đi thăm tù hoặc bị bắt giam, phần lớn điều chúng ta biết về tù ngục chỉ là từ ti vi hay các phương tiện truyền thông.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Until more research is conducted it is difficult to draw any conclusions from these studies.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151010T062141Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151010T062141Z">
        <seg>Cho đến khi có nhiều nghiên cứu được thực hiện hơn thì bây giờ vẫn còn khó khăn trong việc đưa ra bất cứ kết luận nào từ những nghiên cứu này.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Until the 1950s this law required a woman to ‘resist to the utmost’ if unwanted intercourse was to be recognized as rape.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T034613Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T033132Z">
        <seg>Từ những năm 1950, luật này được đề nghị 'bảo vệ tối đa' phụ nữ nếu giao hợp ngoài mong muốn được coi như là hiếp dâm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Victim surveys, for example the 2005 British Crime Survey (Nicholas et al., 2005), show higher levels of sex offending than are reported to the police and it is commonly accepted that there is a high proportion of hidden sexual victimization.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151008T160349Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151008T154506Z">
        <seg>Những cuộc khảo sát nạn nhân, ví dụ theo Khảo sát Tội phạm Anh Quốc 2005 (Nicholas et al., 2005), cho thấy nạn quấy rối tình dục lớn hơn nhiều so với những trường hợp được cảnh sát ghi lại và thường được chấp nhận rằng có một tỉ lệ lớn các vụ ngược đãi tình dục bị che đậy.    </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Victimization by prisoners/prison staff.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151010T061810Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151010T061810Z">
        <seg>Bị ngược đãi bởi bạn tù hoặc cai ngục.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Victimization.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T172444Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T172444Z">
        <seg>Bị ngược đãi.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>We are used to the notion of society or the State punishing law- breakers for their wrongdoings, but what do citizens actually think about punishment, and who should be punished?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151010T031128Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151010T031128Z">
        <seg>Chúng ta đã quen với ý niệm về 1 xã hội howcj 1 nhà nước trừng phạt những người phá luật vì những hành vi phạm phap của họ nhưng những công dân thực sự nghĩ gì về việc trừng phạt và ai nên bị trừng phạt?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>We often hear about the supposed deterrent effect of imprisonment when we hear politicians talking about ‘getting tough on crime’.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T160904Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T160904Z">
        <seg>Chúng ta thường nghe về việc ngăn ngừa phạm tội khi nghe các nhà chính trị nhắc đến việc "gia tăng tội phạm"’.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>We usually left our families on a Sunday, getting on a coach with all the other officers, returning the following Friday – there was a lot of couples who separated in police families that year.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T144625Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151009T145712Z">
        <seg>Chúng tôi thường tạm biệt gia đình vào Chủ nhật, bắt đầu buổi huấn luyện với tất cả đồng nghiệp khác, về nhà vào Thứ sáu tuần sau - có rất nhiều cặp đôi đã bị chia tách trong năm ấy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>We were all young and fit, but this routine tired us all out so that at the end of the week we got off the coaches like old men.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T145226Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151011T145226Z">
        <seg>Tất cả đều trẻ và khỏe mạnh, nhưng ngày nào cũng như vậy khiến chúng tôi vô cùng mệt mỏi nên cuối tuần chúng tôi ra khỏi trại huấn luyện như những ông già .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>We were usually living in such places as drill halls, sometimes sleeping on the floor, living out of a kitbag.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151011T150717Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151009T145521Z">
        <seg>Chúng tôi thường sống trong những nơi như phòng tập quân đội, đôi lúc ngủ dưới sàn, sinh hoạt chỉ với một túi đựng đồ dùng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>What are your views on the rehabilitation of offenders?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Nga" changedate="20151011T045343Z" creationid="Nga" creationdate="20151011T045343Z">
        <seg>Quan điểm của bạn ra sao về việc cải tạo phạm nhân?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>What is Preface?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Dale Nguyen" changedate="20151006T153243Z" creationid="Dale Nguyen" creationdate="20151006T153243Z">
        <seg>Lời Mở Đầu Là Gì?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>What is considered acceptable by society, to what extent this differs between societies or cultures, and how has this changed throughout history will be just some of the topics discussed in this chapter.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T150710Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151006T164027Z">
        <seg>Điều mà xã hội cho là có thể chấp nhận được,ở mức độ mà điều này thay đổi giữa xã hội hoặc nền văn hóa khác nhau và cách điều này thay đổi trong suốt lịch sử sẽ là 1 trong sô những chủ đề được đề cập đến trong chương này.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>When some newspaper reports condemn prisons for being more like holiday camps and state that life in prison is too easy, they are contrasting what they believe prison to be like with the perceived goals of imprisonment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T160306Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T160306Z">
        <seg>Trong khi có rất nhiều bài báo lên án việc các nhà tù đang trở nên giống như những trại nghỉ dưỡng và rằng cuộc sống ở trong tù quá dễ dàng, điều này trái người với những gì vốn được tin là mục đích thực sự của việc giam giữ.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>When the defendant is asked how he knows that ‘this wasn’t something that she didn’t want to do’ he replies ‘she never said “no”, she never said “stop” and when I was kissing her she was kissing me back’ (Ehrlich, 2003, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151010T025152Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151010T025152Z">
        <seg>Khi bị cáo được hỏi làm thế nào anh ta biết đó là cái gì đó mà cô ấy không muốn, anh ta trả lời cô ấy không bao giờ nói "không" cô ấy không bao giờ nói "dừng lại" và khi tôi hôn cô ta và cô ta cũng hôn tôi.’ (Ehrlich, 2003, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>While chapter 10 outlines the research on the rehabilitation of offenders, this chapter will introduce you to the research con- ducted on how being imprisoned can affect prisoners and how they cope with this experience.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T151909Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T151909Z">
        <seg>Chương 10 sẽ tóm tắt các nghiên cứu về sự tái hòa nhập của người phạm tội. Còn trong chương này, bạn đọc  sẽ được giới thiệu các nghiên cứu về tác động của việc bắt giam tới tù nhân và cách thức họ xoay sở với nó.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>While punishments may change, they are still based on a small number of theories for punishing offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T151709Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T151709Z">
        <seg>Trong khi nhiều sự trừng phạt có thể thay đổi, chúng vẫn dựa trên 1 số giả thuyết về việc trừng phạt kẻ có tội.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>While the risk principle states that the duration or dosage of the treatment should be linked to the risk that the particular offender presents, the need principle states that the programme should address the criminogenic needs of the offenders that attend it.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T024514Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T024514Z">
        <seg>Trong khi nguyên tắc nguy cơ phát biểu rằng khoảng thời gian và liều lượng của chương trình điều trị nên liên kết với nguy cơ mà phạm nhân đặc biệt biểu hiện, thì nguyên tắc nhu cầu cho rằng chương trình nên bàn đến các nhu cầu dẫn đến phạm tội của những phạm nhân tham gia điều trị. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>While this indicator is useful from a policy perspective, it is only an approximation of reoffending.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T120047Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T155808Z">
        <seg>Trong khi yếu tố chỉ thị rất hữu dụng với một quan điểm cư xử, nhưng thật ra nó chỉ là việc gần như tái phạm của người.  </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>With a limited pool of resources, the risk principle states that intervention should be targeted towards those who are most likely to gain from it.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T153530Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T105134Z">
        <seg>Với nguồn lực có hạn, nguyên tắc nguy cơ đã phát biểu rằng việc can thiệp nên được đặt mục tiêu đối với những ai hầu như có khả năng hồi phục. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Younger inmates.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="yuko" changedate="20151009T034605Z" creationid="yuko" creationdate="20151009T034605Z">
        <seg>Bạn tù trẻ hơn.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>Your daily routine is dictated by the prison routine, and choices, such as what you will have for your dinner or what time you will get up in the morning, are no longer available.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T162205Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T162205Z">
        <seg>Thói quen hàng ngày của bạn sẽ bị chi phối theo quy định của nhà tù. Và những lựa chọn chẳng hạn như bạn sẽ ăn gì vào bữa tối hay sáng mai bạn dậy lúc mấy giờ sẽ không còn thực hiện được.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>aspects&lt;t0/&gt; of the investigation.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T123229Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151007T013238Z">
        <seg>Những khía cạnh trong công việc điều tra</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>assessment&lt;t0/&gt; of offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151008T162408Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151008T162408Z">
        <seg>Đánh giá của phạm nhân.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>attitudes and beliefs in punishment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151010T030911Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151010T030911Z">
        <seg>Thái độ và niềm tin vào việc trừng phạt.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>characteristics of the prison environment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T155619Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T155619Z">
        <seg>Đặc điểm của môi trường nhà tù.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>courtroom  language&lt;t0/&gt;.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151007T005206Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151007T005206Z">
        <seg>Ngôn ngữ phòng xử án&lt;t0/&gt;.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>detecting&lt;t0/&gt; deception from &lt;t1/&gt;behavioural&lt;t2/&gt; cues.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T085620Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T085526Z">
        <seg>Phát hiện&lt;t0/&gt;sự lừa dối từ &lt;t1/&gt;các dấu hiệu hành vi &lt;t2/&gt; </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>detecting&lt;t0/&gt; deception.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="nguye" changedate="20151010T085457Z" creationid="nguye" creationdate="20151010T085457Z">
        <seg>Phát hiện &lt;t0/&gt; sự lừa dối</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>experiencing imprisonment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T151735Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T151735Z">
        <seg>Trải nghiệm trong tù</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>forensic&lt;t0/&gt; linguistics.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="PhuongThao" changedate="20151009T004625Z" creationid="PhuongThao" creationdate="20151009T004625Z">
        <seg>Ngôn ngữ học pháp lý</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>history and philosophy of punishment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151007T150743Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151007T150743Z">
        <seg>Lịch sử và tính triết lý của việc trừng phạt .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>how&lt;t0/&gt; is a sexual offender defined?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153356Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153356Z">
        <seg>Định nghĩa một tội phạm tình dục như thế nào?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>legal&lt;t0/&gt; language reform.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="dinhquy" changedate="20151012T131407Z" creationid="dinhquy" creationdate="20151012T131407Z">
        <seg>cải cách ngôn ngữ pháp lý.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>offender profiling and linking crime.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T032445Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T024419Z">
        <seg>Thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm và xâu chuỗi tội ác.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>offender profiling.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Hx" changedate="20151008T033523Z" creationid="Hx" creationdate="20151008T033523Z">
        <seg>Thiết lập hồ sơ tội phạm.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>public perceptions of the police.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Jennifer Tran" changedate="20151006T153700Z" creationid="Jennifer Tran" creationdate="20151006T153700Z">
        <seg>Những nhận thức của công chúng về lực lượng cảnh sát.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>punishment and offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Lenovo" changedate="20151006T161347Z" creationid="Lenovo" creationdate="20151006T161347Z">
        <seg>Sự trừng phạt và người phạm tội </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>special&lt;t0/&gt; situations.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Admin" changedate="20151006T191226Z" creationid="Admin" creationdate="20151006T191226Z">
        <seg>Những tình huống đặc biệt.&lt;t0/&gt;</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>the physical environment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="LHC" changedate="20151011T161635Z" creationid="LHC" creationdate="20151011T161635Z">
        <seg>Môi trường nhà tù</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>the&lt;t0/&gt; homology assumption.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="The sun" changedate="20151006T162301Z" creationid="The sun" creationdate="20151006T162301Z">
        <seg>Giả định tương đồng</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>the&lt;t0/&gt; management and treatment of sex offenders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151007T153201Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151007T130246Z">
        <seg>Quản lý và điều trị tội phạm tình dục.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>the&lt;t0/&gt; need principle</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151010T023958Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151010T023958Z">
        <seg>Nguyên tắc nhu cầu</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>the&lt;t0/&gt; rehabilitation of offenders:</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Nga" changedate="20151006T154725Z" creationid="Nga" creationdate="20151006T154725Z">
        <seg>Quá trình cải tạo phạm nhân:</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>the&lt;t0/&gt; responsivity principle.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ENVY" changedate="20151007T141645Z" creationid="ENVY" creationdate="20151007T141645Z">
        <seg>the&lt;t0/&gt; Nguyên tắc đáp ứng.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>the&lt;t0/&gt; risk principle.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="USER" changedate="20151009T103249Z" creationid="USER" creationdate="20151009T103249Z">
        <seg>Nguyên tắc nguy cơ</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>voice&lt;t0/&gt; identification is more difficult than visual identification;</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="ADMIN" changedate="20151012T124558Z" creationid="ADMIN" creationdate="20151012T124558Z">
        <seg>nhận dạng giọng nói khó hơn nhiều so với nhận diện bằng mắt;</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>what&lt;t0/&gt; causes sexual offending?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Demon" changedate="20151012T153626Z" creationid="Demon" creationdate="20151012T153626Z">
        <seg>Điều gì gây ra xâm phạm tình dục?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="EN-US">
        <seg>what&lt;t0/&gt; works?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="VI" changeid="Nga" changedate="20151006T154807Z" creationid="Nga" creationdate="20151006T154807Z">
        <seg>Liệu có hiệu quả?&lt;t0/&gt;</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
<!-- Alternative translations -->
  </body>
</tmx>
